for	O	O
although	O	O
the	O	O
chinese	O	O
took	O	O
impressions	O	O
from	O	O
wood	O	O
blocks	O	O
engraved	O	O
in	O	O
relief	O	O
for	O	O
centuries	O	O
before	O	O
the	O	O
woodcutters	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
netherlands	LOC	LOC
by	O	O
a	O	O
similar	O	O
process	O	O
what	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
bible	O	O
actually	O	O
dated	O	O
which	O	O
also	O	O
was	O	O
printed	O	O
at	O	O
mace	LOC	LOC
by	O	O
peter	PER	PER
shaffer	PER	PER
in	O	O
the	O	O
year	O	O
1462	O	O
especially	O	O
as	O	O
regards	O	O
to	O	O
lowercase	O	O
letters	O	O
and	O	O
type	O	O
very	O	O
similar	O	O
was	O	O
used	O	O
during	O	O
the	O	O
next	O	O
15	O	O
or	O	O
20	O	O
years	O	O
not	O	O
only	O	O
by	O	O
chauffeur	PER	O
buy	O	O
printers	O	O
in	O	O
strasburg	LOC	LOC
basil	O	ORG
paris	LOC	LOC
lubec	LOC	ORG
and	O	O
other	O	O
cities	O	O
but	O	O
don	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
expect	O	O
in	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
letter	O	O
with	O	O
most	O	O
often	O	O
used	O	O
a	O	O
very	O	O
few	O	O
years	O	O
saw	O	O
the	O	O
birth	O	O
of	O	O
roman	O	O
character	O	O
not	O	O
only	O	O
in	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
but	O	O
in	O	O
germany	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
france	LOC	LOC
1465	O	O
swain	PER	ORG
haim	PER	PER
and	O	O
pennartz	PER	PER
began	O	O
printing	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
monastery	O	O
of	O	O
subiaco	LOC	LOC
near	O	O
rome	LOC	LOC
printed	O	O
very	O	O
few	O	O
books	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
type	O	O
3	O	O
only	O	O
but	O	O
in	O	O
their	O	O
very	O	O
first	O	O
book	O	O
syndrome	O	O
beginning	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
year	O	O
1468	O	O
about	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
year	O	O
mental	O	O
in	O	O
at	O	O
strasburg	LOC	LOC
began	O	O
to	O	O
print	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
type	O	O
which	O	O
is	O	O
distinctly	O	O
roman	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
next	O	O
year	O	O
gunther	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
designer	O	O
at	O	O
augsburg	LOC	LOC
followed	O	O
suit	O	O
1470	O	O
at	O	O
paris	LOC	LOC
associates	O	O
turned	O	O
out	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
books	O	O
printed	O	O
in	O	O
france	LOC	LOC
also	O	O
in	O	O
roman	O	O
character	O	O
it	O	O
must	O	O
be	O	O
said	O	O
that	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
in	O	O
no	O	O
way	O	O
like	O	O
the	O	O
transition	O	O
type	O	O
of	O	O
subiaco	LOC	O
and	O	O
though	O	O
more	O	O
roman	O	O
than	O	O
that	O	O
yet	O	O
scarcely	O	O
more	O	O
like	O	O
the	O	O
complete	O	O
roman	O	O
type	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
earliest	O	O
printers	O	O
of	O	O
rome	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
further	O	O
development	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
roman	O	O
letter	O	O
took	O	O
place	O	O
at	O	O
venice	LOC	LOC
john	PER	PER
of	O	O
spiders	O	O
and	O	O
his	O	O
brother	O	O
vendelin	PER	PER
began	O	O
to	O	O
print	O	O
bob	PER	PER
jensen	PER	PER
it	O	O
must	O	O
be	O	O
said	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
carried	O	O
the	O	O
development	O	O
of	O	O
roman	O	O
type	O	O
as	O	O
far	O	O
as	O	O
it	O	O
can	O	O
go	O	O
after	O	O
his	O	O
death	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
1480s	O	O
or	O	O
at	O	O
least	O	O
by	O	O
1490	O	O
printing	O	O
in	O	O
venice	LOC	LOC
had	O	O
declined	O	O
very	O	O
much	O	O
and	O	O
though	O	O
the	O	O
famous	O	O
family	O	O
of	O	O
aldis	PER	ORG
restored	O	O
its	O	O
technical	O	O
excellence	O	O
rejecting	O	O
battered	O	O
letters	O	O
yet	O	O
their	O	O
type	O	O
is	O	O
artistically	O	O
on	O	O
a	O	O
much	O	O
lower	O	O
level	O	O
than	O	O
jensen	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
and	O	O
in	O	O
fact	O	O
they	O	O
must	O	O
be	O	O
considered	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
ended	O	O
the	O	O
age	O	O
of	O	O
fine	O	O
printing	O	O
in	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
jensen	PER	PER
however	O	O
had	O	O
many	O	O
contemporaries	O	O
who	O	O
use	O	O
beautiful	O	O
type	O	O
some	O	O
of	O	O
which	O	O
as	O	O
eg	O	O
that	O	O
of	O	O
jacobus	PER	PER
rubeus	PER	PER
or	O	O
jacques	PER	PER
lu	PER	PER
is	O	O
scarcely	O	O
distinguishable	O	O
from	O	O
his	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
these	O	O
great	O	O
venetian	O	O
printers	O	O
together	O	O
with	O	O
their	O	O
brethren	O	O
of	O	O
rome	LOC	LOC
milan	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
one	O	O
or	O	O
two	O	O
other	O	O
cities	O	O
who	O	O
produced	O	O
the	O	O
splendid	O	O
editions	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
classics	O	O
which	O	O
are	O	O
one	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
glories	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
printers	O	O
are	O	O
even	O	O
in	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
most	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
field	O	O
logical	O	O
and	O	O
law	O	O
books	O	O
were	O	O
printed	O	O
in	O	O
gothic	O	O
letter	O	O
many	O	O
of	O	O
whose	O	O
types	O	O
indeed	O	O
like	O	O
that	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
subiaco	LOC	ORG
works	O	O
are	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
transitional	O	O
character	O	O
this	O	O
was	O	O
notably	O	O
the	O	O
case	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
early	O	O
works	O	O
printed	O	O
at	O	O
home	O	O
and	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
somewhat	O	O
lesser	O	O
degree	O	O
at	O	O
augsburg	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
fact	O	O
gunther	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
designers	O	O
first	O	O
type	O	O
afterwards	O	O
used	O	O
by	O	O
schussler	PER	PER
is	O	O
remarkably	O	O
like	O	O
the	O	O
type	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
before	O	O
mentioned	O	O
subiaco	LOC	ORG
books	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
low	O	LOC
countries	O	LOC
and	O	O
cologne	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
were	O	O
very	O	O
fertile	O	O
of	O	O
printed	O	O
books	O	O
gothic	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
favorite	O	O
the	O	O
characteristic	O	O
dutch	O	O
type	O	O
as	O	O
represented	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
excellent	O	O
printer	O	O
lou	PER	O
is	O	O
very	O	O
pronounced	O	O
and	O	O
uncompromising	O	O
this	O	O
type	O	O
was	O	O
introduced	O	O
into	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
by	O	O
winkin	PER	PER
to	O	O
word	O	O
paxton	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
successor	O	O
most	O	O
of	O	O
caxton	PER	O
zone	O	O
types	O	O
of	O	O
an	O	O
earlier	O	O
character	O	O
after	O	O
the	O	O
end	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
fifteenth	O	O
century	O	O
the	O	O
depredations	O	O
of	O	O
printing	O	O
especially	O	O
in	O	O
germany	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
england	LOC	LOC
about	O	O
this	O	O
time	O	O
an	O	O
attempt	O	O
was	O	O
made	O	O
notably	O	O
by	O	O
castle	PER	ORG
on	O	ORG
who	O	O
started	O	O
business	O	O
in	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
as	O	O
a	O	O
type	O	O
founder	O	O
in	O	O
1720	O	O
ashland	LOC	LOC
'	O	O
s	O	O
type	O	O
is	O	O
clear	O	O
and	O	O
neat	O	O
and	O	O
fairly	O	O
well	O	O
design	O	O
where	O	O
the	O	O
17th	O	O
century	O	O
letters	O	O
are	O	O
at	O	O
least	O	O
pure	O	O
and	O	O
simple	O	O
inline	O	O
the	O	O
italian	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
frenchman	O	O
dido	PER	O
are	O	O
the	O	O
leaders	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
luckless	O	O
change	O	O
though	O	O
our	O	O
own	O	O
baskerville	O	PER
who	O	O
was	O	O
at	O	O
work	O	O
some	O	O
years	O	O
before	O	O
them	O	O
went	O	O
much	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
lines	O	O
chiswick	LOC	LOC
press	O	O
in	O	O
1844	O	O
revived	O	O
castle	O	ORG
on	O	O
stops	O	O
printing	O	O
for	O	O
measures	O	O
the	O	O
diary	O	O
of	O	O
lady	O	O
willoughby	PER	PER
this	O	O
experiment	O	O
was	O	O
so	O	O
far	O	O
successful	O	O
that	O	O
about	O	O
1850	O	O
measures	O	O
miller	PER	PER
and	O	O
richard	PER	PER
attenborough	PER	PER
now	O	O
come	O	O
into	O	O
general	O	O
use	O	O
that	O	O
are	O	O
obviously	O	O
a	O	O
great	O	O
improvement	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
ordinary	O	O
modern	O	O
style	O	O
and	O	O
use	O	O
in	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
is	O	O
in	O	O
fact	O	O
the	O	O
bodony	PER	O
type	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
discouraging	O	O
to	O	O
note	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
improvement	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
last	O	O
50	O	O
years	O	O
is	O	O
almost	O	O
wholly	O	O
confined	O	O
to	O	O
great	LOC	LOC
britain	LOC	LOC
here	O	O
and	O	O
there	O	O
a	O	O
book	O	O
is	O	O
printed	O	O
in	O	O
france	LOC	LOC
or	O	O
germany	LOC	LOC
with	O	O
some	O	O
pretension	O	O
to	O	O
good	O	O
taste	O	O
italy	LOC	LOC
is	O	O
contentedly	O	O
stagnant	O	O
america	LOC	LOC
has	O	O
produced	O	O
a	O	O
good	O	O
many	O	O
show	O	O
me	O	O
books	O	O
the	O	O
typography	O	O
paper	O	O
and	O	O
illustrations	O	O
of	O	O
which	O	O
are	O	O
however	O	O
even	O	O
the	O	O
cast	O	O
one	O	O
type	O	O
when	O	O
enlarged	O	O
shows	O	O
great	O	O
shortcomings	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
respect	O	O
instead	O	O
of	O	O
ending	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
sharp	O	O
and	O	O
clear	O	O
stroke	O	O
of	O	O
jensen	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
letters	O	O
this	O	O
is	O	O
awkward	O	O
if	O	O
you	O	O
have	O	O
to	O	O
read	O	O
bradshaw	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
died	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
hurry	O	O
most	O	O
of	O	O
jensen	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
letters	O	O
are	O	O
designed	O	O
with	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
square	O	O
that	O	O
made	O	O
in	O	O
america	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
is	O	O
the	O	O
worst	O	O
conceivable	O	O
the	O	O
position	O	O
of	O	O
our	O	O
society	O	O
that	O	O
don	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
work	O	O
of	O	O
utility	O	O
might	O	O
be	O	O
also	O	O
a	O	O
work	O	O
of	O	O
art	O	O
if	O	O
we	O	O
care	O	O
to	O	O
make	O	O
it	O	O
so	O	O
the	O	O
chronicles	O	O
of	O	O
nougat	O	O
volume	O	O
to	O	O
arthur	PER	PER
griffiths	PER	PER
section	O	O
for	O	O
new	O	LOC
gate	O	LOC
down	O	LOC
to	O	O
1818	O	O
with	O	O
criminals	O	O
and	O	O
misdemeanants	O	O
of	O	O
all	O	O
shades	O	O
crowding	O	O
perpetually	O	O
into	O	O
its	O	O
narrow	O	O
limits	O	O
the	O	O
letter	O	O
state	O	O
of	O	O
new	LOC	O
gate	LOC	O
was	O	O
worse	O	O
than	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
neeld	PER	PER
gives	O	O
some	O	O
figures	O	O
which	O	O
will	O	O
illustrate	O	O
this	O	O
the	O	O
numbers	O	O
soon	O	O
increased	O	O
however	O	O
and	O	O
by	O	O
1811	O	O
had	O	O
again	O	O
risen	O	O
to	O	O
629	O	O
and	O	O
mr	O	O
nield	PER	PER
was	O	O
told	O	O
that	O	O
there	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
at	O	O
one	O	O
time	O	O
300	O	O
debtors	O	O
and	O	O
900	O	O
criminals	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
or	O	O
1200	O	O
prisoners	O	O
in	O	O
all	O	O
previous	O	O
to	O	O
that	O	O
date	O	O
there	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
700	O	O
or	O	O
800	O	O
frequently	O	O
and	O	O
once	O	O
in	O	O
mr	O	O
eckermann	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
time	O	O
1000	O	O
the	O	O
adequacy	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
was	O	O
noticed	O	O
and	O	O
reported	O	O
upon	O	O
again	O	O
and	O	O
again	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
seldom	O	O
let	O	O
a	O	O
session	O	O
go	O	O
by	O	O
without	O	O
visiting	O	O
you	O	O
gate	O	O
the	O	O
grand	O	O
jury	O	O
made	O	O
a	O	O
special	O	O
presentment	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
court	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
common	O	ORG
council	ORG	ORG
pointing	O	O
out	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
side	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
intended	O	O
for	O	O
only	O	O
100	O	O
returns	O	O
laid	O	O
before	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
showed	O	O
that	O	O
6439	O	O
persons	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
nougat	O	O
this	O	O
number	O	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
include	O	O
the	O	O
debtors	O	O
a	O	O
numerous	O	O
class	O	O
who	O	O
were	O	O
still	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
pending	O	O
the	O	O
completion	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
in	O	O
order	O	O
to	O	O
realize	O	O
the	O	O
evil	O	O
entailed	O	O
by	O	O
incarceration	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
these	O	O
days	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
necessary	O	O
to	O	O
give	O	O
some	O	O
account	O	O
of	O	O
its	O	O
interior	O	O
full	O	O
details	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
arrangements	O	O
are	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
found	O	O
in	O	O
mr	O	O
neil	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
state	O	O
of	O	O
prisons	O	O
in	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
scotland	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
wales	LOC	LOC
published	O	O
in	O	O
1812	O	O
neeld	PER	PER
takes	O	O
it	O	O
for	O	O
granted	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
former	O	O
rather	O	O
than	O	O
the	O	O
latter	O	O
prevailed	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
selection	O	O
the	O	O
long	O	O
narrow	O	O
yard	O	O
still	O	O
remained	O	O
as	O	O
we	O	O
saw	O	O
it	O	O
in	O	O
jacobite	O	O
times	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
top	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
continues	O	O
neeld	PER	ORG
arawatch	O	ORG
house	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
century	O	O
box	O	O
where	O	O
two	O	O
or	O	O
more	O	O
guards	O	O
with	O	O
dogs	O	O
and	O	O
firearms	O	O
neeld	PER	PER
gives	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
authority	O	O
of	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
burchell	PER	PER
the	O	O
undersheriff	O	O
of	O	O
middlesex	LOC	LOC
table	O	O
showing	O	O
the	O	O
figures	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
year	O	O
ending	O	O
michael	PER	O
miss	O	O
1802	O	O
15000	O	O
of	O	O
these	O	O
were	O	O
issued	O	O
in	O	O
middlesex	LOC	LOC
alone	O	O
which	O	O
at	O	O
that	O	O
time	O	O
was	O	O
reckoned	O	O
as	O	O
only	O	O
a	O	O
15th	O	O
of	O	O
great	LOC	LOC
britain	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
number	O	O
of	O	O
arrests	O	O
actually	O	O
made	O	O
was	O	O
114300	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
kingdom	LOC	O
and	O	O
7024	O	O
middlesex	LOC	ORG
neeld	PER	PER
also	O	O
says	O	O
that	O	O
in	O	O
1793	O	O
5719	O	O
ricks	PER	O
and	O	O
executions	O	O
for	O	O
decks	O	O
between	O	O
10	O	O
lb	O	O
and	O	O
20	O	O
lb	O	O
were	O	O
issued	O	O
in	O	O
middlesex	LOC	LOC
alfred	PER	PER
the	PER	PER
great	PER	PER
established	O	O
the	O	O
court	ORG	O
baron	ORG	O
the	O	O
hundred	ORG	LOC
court	ORG	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
county	ORG	O
court	ORG	O
which	O	O
among	O	O
other	O	O
matters	O	O
entertain	O	O
please	O	O
for	O	O
debt	O	O
lake	ORG	LOC
county	ORG	O
court	ORG	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
sheriff	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
who	O	O
said	O	O
they	O	O
'	O	O
re	O	O
surrounded	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
bishop	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
magnets	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
county	O	O
but	O	O
as	O	O
time	O	O
passed	O	O
difficulties	O	O
and	O	O
delays	O	O
in	O	O
obtaining	O	O
judgment	O	O
led	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
removal	O	O
of	O	O
causes	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
court	ORG	ORG
of	O	ORG
king	O	ORG
'	O	ORG
s	O	ORG
bench	O	ORG
so	O	O
much	O	O
inconvenience	O	O
ensued	O	O
that	O	O
in	O	O
1518	O	O
the	O	O
corporation	O	O
obtained	O	O
from	O	O
parliament	ORG	O
and	O	O
act	O	O
empowering	O	O
to	O	O
alderman	O	O
four	O	O
common	O	O
councilman	O	O
to	O	O
hold	O	O
courts	O	O
of	O	ORG
requests	O	ORG
or	O	O
courts	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
conscience	O	ORG
to	O	O
hear	O	O
and	O	O
determine	O	O
all	O	O
causes	O	O
of	O	O
death	O	O
these	O	O
courts	O	O
were	O	O
extended	O	O
to	O	O
centuries	O	O
later	O	O
to	O	O
several	O	O
large	O	O
provincial	O	O
towns	O	O
and	O	O
all	O	O
were	O	O
in	O	O
full	O	O
activity	O	O
when	O	O
nield	PER	O
road	O	O
the	O	O
activity	O	O
as	O	O
well	O	O
as	O	O
the	O	O
futility	O	O
of	O	O
these	O	O
courts	O	O
may	O	O
be	O	O
estimated	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
statement	O	O
given	O	O
by	O	O
neil	PER	PER
1312	O	O
debtors	O	O
were	O	O
committed	O	O
by	O	O
them	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
between	O	O
1797	O	O
and	O	O
1808	O	O
field	PER	PER
found	O	O
at	O	O
his	O	O
visit	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1810	O	O
amongst	O	O
others	O	O
thomas	PER	PER
blackburn	PER	PER
had	O	O
been	O	O
committed	O	O
on	O	O
october	O	O
15th	O	O
for	O	O
a	O	O
debt	O	O
of	O	O
one	O	O
shilling	O	O
five	O	O
pence	O	O
thomas	PER	PER
dobson	PER	PER
on	O	O
22nd	O	O
august	O	O
1799	O	O
for	O	O
one	O	O
shilling	O	O
with	O	O
costs	O	O
of	O	O
eight	O	O
shillings	O	O
ten	O	O
pence	O	O
and	O	O
susanna	PER	PER
evans	PER	PER
in	O	O
october	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
year	O	O
for	O	O
two	O	O
shillings	O	O
with	O	O
cost	O	O
6	O	O
shillings	O	O
a	O	O
pence	O	O
other	O	O
cases	O	O
are	O	O
recorded	O	O
elsewhere	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
gilts	O	O
1st	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
concert	O	O
where	O	O
in	O	O
1805	O	O
mister	O	O
kneeled	PER	O
found	O	O
a	O	O
man	O	O
named	O	O
william	PER	PER
grant	PER	PER
and	O	O
john	PER	PER
lancaster	PER	PER
for	O	O
one	O	O
shilling	O	O
a	O	O
test	O	O
with	O	O
costs	O	O
of	O	O
7	O	O
shillings	O	O
sixpence	O	O
quote	O	O
these	O	O
surely	O	O
i	O	O
thought	O	O
says	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
neal	PER	PER
were	O	O
bad	O	O
enough	O	O
but	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
not	O	O
so	O	O
and	O	O
quote	O	O
he	O	O
recites	O	O
another	O	O
most	O	O
outrageous	O	O
and	O	O
extraordinary	O	O
case	O	O
in	O	O
which	O	O
one	O	O
john	PER	PER
byrd	PER	PER
bird	O	PER
was	O	O
however	O	O
discharged	O	O
within	O	O
3	O	O
days	O	O
by	O	O
a	O	O
subscription	O	O
raised	O	O
among	O	O
his	O	O
fellow	O	O
prisoners	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
in	O	O
his	O	O
inquiry	O	O
into	O	O
the	O	O
system	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
discipline	O	O
aladdin	O	PER
question	O	O
was	O	O
found	O	O
in	O	O
coldbath	LOC	LOC
fields	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
to	O	O
which	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
sent	O	O
for	O	O
a	O	O
month	O	O
in	O	O
default	O	O
of	O	O
paying	O	O
a	O	O
fine	O	O
of	O	O
forty	O	O
shillings	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
employ	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
corn	O	O
chandler	PER	O
at	O	O
islington	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
went	O	O
into	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
with	O	O
his	O	O
master	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
cart	O	O
and	O	O
horse	O	O
there	O	O
was	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
road	O	O
a	O	O
temporary	O	O
bar	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
collector	O	O
of	O	O
tolls	O	O
who	O	O
was	O	O
sometimes	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
spot	O	O
and	O	O
sometimes	O	O
not	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
friends	O	O
at	O	O
once	O	O
paid	O	O
the	O	O
forty	O	O
shillings	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
boy	O	O
was	O	O
released	O	O
neil	PER	PER
'	O	PER
s	O	PER
gives	O	O
a	O	O
list	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
various	O	O
items	O	O
charged	O	O
upon	O	O
a	O	O
debt	O	O
of	O	O
10	O	O
lb	O	O
which	O	O
included	O	O
instructions	O	O
to	O	O
sue	O	O
before	O	O
dealing	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
debtors	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
prefer	O	O
incidentally	O	O
to	O	O
those	O	O
in	O	O
other	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
prisons	O	O
for	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
gate	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
not	O	O
the	O	O
only	O	O
place	O	O
of	O	O
durance	O	O
for	O	O
these	O	O
unfortunate	O	O
people	O	O
there	O	O
were	O	O
also	O	O
the	O	O
kings	ORG	ORG
bench	ORG	O
the	ORG	O
fleet	ORG	ORG
and	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
especially	O	O
devoted	O	O
to	O	O
them	O	O
whilst	O	O
ludgate	ORG	O
the	O	O
gilts	O	O
1st	ORG	O
street	ORG	O
and	O	O
borrow	ORG	O
comforters	ORG	O
also	O	O
received	O	O
them	O	O
the	O	O
kings	ORG	ORG
bench	ORG	LOC
was	O	O
a	O	O
national	O	O
prison	O	O
in	O	O
which	O	O
were	O	O
confined	O	O
all	O	O
debtors	O	O
arrested	O	O
for	O	O
debt	O	O
or	O	O
for	O	O
contempt	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
court	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
the	O	O
kings	ORG	ORG
bench	ORG	ORG
the	O	O
best	O	O
or	O	O
at	O	O
least	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
influential	O	O
prisoners	O	O
god	O	PER
lodging	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
statehouse	O	O
which	O	O
contained	O	O
eight	O	O
large	O	O
handsome	O	O
rooms	O	O
keeper	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
large	O	O
tap	O	O
room	O	O
called	O	O
the	O	O
brace	O	O
because	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
once	O	O
kept	O	O
by	O	O
two	O	O
brothers	O	O
named	O	O
partridge	PER	PER
also	O	O
paid	O	O
him	O	O
toll	O	O
the	O	O
sale	O	O
of	O	O
spirits	O	O
was	O	O
forbidden	O	O
but	O	O
june	O	O
could	O	O
always	O	O
be	O	O
had	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
whistling	O	O
shops	O	O
where	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
known	O	O
as	O	O
moonshine	O	O
sky	O	O
blue	O	O
mexico	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
was	O	O
consumed	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
rate	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
hogshead	O	O
per	O	O
week	O	O
the	O	O
fleet	O	ORG
which	O	O
stood	O	O
in	O	O
farrington	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
what	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
a	O	O
prison	O	O
for	O	O
debtors	O	O
and	O	O
persons	O	O
committed	O	O
for	O	O
contempt	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
courts	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
chancery	ORG	ORG
exchequer	ORG	ORG
and	O	ORG
common	ORG	ORG
pleas	ORG	ORG
it	O	O
was	O	O
so	O	O
used	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
date	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
abolition	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
star	O	O
chamber	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
sixteenth	O	O
charles	PER	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
shameful	O	O
malpractices	O	O
of	O	O
bambridge	PER	PER
the	O	O
warden	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
fleet	O	ORG
at	O	O
the	O	O
commencement	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
18th	O	O
century	O	O
are	O	O
too	O	O
well	O	O
known	O	O
to	O	O
need	O	O
more	O	O
than	O	O
a	O	O
passing	O	O
reference	O	O
committee	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
investigated	O	O
the	O	O
charges	O	O
against	O	O
bambridge	PER	PER
who	O	O
was	O	O
proved	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
connived	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
escape	O	O
went	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
guilty	O	O
of	O	O
extortion	O	O
two	O	O
others	O	O
one	O	O
sir	O	O
william	PER	PER
rich	PER	PER
baronet	PER	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
loaded	O	O
with	O	O
heavy	O	O
irons	O	O
in	O	O
consequence	O	O
of	O	O
these	O	O
disclosures	O	O
bambridge	PER	PER
and	O	O
hugging	O	O
his	O	O
predecessor	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
office	O	O
or	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	ORG
the	O	O
committee	ORG	ORG
on	ORG	ORG
jails	ORG	ORG
reported	O	O
that	O	O
quote	O	O
although	O	O
the	O	O
house	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
warden	O	O
looked	O	O
into	O	O
the	O	O
court	O	O
senators	O	O
were	O	O
rather	O	O
better	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	O
this	O	O
very	O	O
ancient	O	O
prison	O	O
which	O	O
stood	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
high	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
south	LOC	LOC
were	O	O
was	O	O
used	O	O
for	O	O
debtors	O	O
arrested	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
lowest	O	O
psalms	O	O
within	O	O
12	O	O
miles	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
palace	LOC	LOC
of	LOC	LOC
whitehall	LOC	LOC
also	O	O
for	O	O
prisoners	O	O
committed	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
admiralty	O	ORG
court	O	O
one	O	O
time	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
receptacle	O	O
of	O	O
pirates	O	O
but	O	O
none	O	O
more	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
it	O	O
after	O	O
1789	O	O
the	O	O
court	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
instituted	O	O
by	O	O
charles	PER	PER
the	O	O
first	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
sixth	O	O
year	O	O
of	O	O
his	O	O
reign	O	O
but	O	O
it	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
business	O	O
was	O	O
much	O	O
reduced	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
extension	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
courts	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
conscience	ORG	ORG
the	O	O
prison	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
nest	O	O
of	O	O
abuse	O	O
has	O	O
like	O	O
its	O	O
neighbor	O	O
the	O	O
kings	ORG	ORG
bench	ORG	O
and	O	O
came	O	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
strong	O	O
animated	O	O
version	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jail	ORG	O
committee	ORG	O
of	O	O
1729	O	O
has	O	O
the	O	O
business	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	ORG	LOC
court	ORG	O
declined	O	O
the	O	O
numbers	O	O
in	O	O
its	O	O
prison	O	O
diminished	O	O
quarreling	O	O
throwing	O	O
water	O	O
over	O	O
being	O	O
sent	O	O
to	O	O
coventry	LOC	LOC
going	O	O
to	O	O
many	O	O
charitable	O	O
gifts	O	O
and	O	O
request	O	O
which	O	O
included	O	O
annual	O	O
donations	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
archbishop	O	O
of	O	O
canterbury	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
lord	PER	O
steward	PER	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
household	O	ORG
the	O	O
stewart	PER	PER
and	O	O
officers	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	ORG	LOC
court	ORG	LOC
and	O	O
others	O	O
left	O	O
by	O	O
a	O	O
mister	O	O
henry	PER	PER
who	O	O
was	O	O
long	O	O
a	O	O
prisoner	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
came	O	O
into	O	O
a	O	O
fortune	O	O
while	O	O
there	O	O
is	O	O
bequest	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
charged	O	O
upon	O	O
his	O	O
manner	O	O
at	O	O
goering	O	O
auxins	O	O
and	O	O
hence	O	O
called	O	O
the	O	O
oxford	ORG	ORG
charity	O	ORG
supreme	O	O
control	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
marshalsea	LOC	O
was	O	O
vested	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
marshal	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
royal	O	O
household	O	O
but	O	O
although	O	O
he	O	O
drew	O	O
a	O	O
salary	O	O
of	O	O
500	O	O
pounds	O	O
a	O	O
year	O	O
comforters	O	O
of	O	O
ludgate	LOC	LOC
giltspur	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
borough	ORG	O
where	O	O
discontinued	O	O
as	O	O
debtors	O	O
prisons	O	O
as	O	O
was	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
also	O	O
show	O	O
me	O	O
opening	O	O
up	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
for	O	O
debtors	O	O
in	O	O
1815	O	O
ludgate	LOC	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
last	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
debtors	O	O
prison	O	O
for	O	O
freeman	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
clergyman	O	O
proctor	O	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
attorneys	O	O
and	O	O
persons	O	O
specially	O	O
selected	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
corporation	O	O
at	O	O
one	O	O
time	O	O
the	O	O
ludgate	ORG	O
debtors	O	O
accompanied	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
keeper	O	O
spruce	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
compton	LOC	LOC
received	O	O
sheriff	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
debtors	O	O
also	O	O
felons	O	O
vagrants	O	O
and	O	O
knight	O	O
charges	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
generally	O	O
crowded	O	O
as	O	O
debtors	O	O
who	O	O
would	O	O
have	O	O
gone	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
poultry	O	O
copter	O	O
we	O	O
sent	O	O
to	O	O
giltspur	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
when	O	O
the	O	O
former	O	O
was	O	O
condemned	O	O
as	O	O
unfit	O	O
to	O	O
receive	O	O
prisoners	O	O
the	O	O
demands	O	O
for	O	O
fees	O	O
were	O	O
excessive	O	O
in	O	O
gilts	LOC	LOC
first	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
borough	LOC	O
compter	LOC	O
was	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
disgraceful	O	O
state	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
last	O	O
the	O	O
men	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
ward	O	O
had	O	O
an	O	O
earth	O	O
or	O	O
rather	O	O
a	O	O
mud	O	O
floor	O	O
in	O	O
one	O	O
room	O	O
mister	O	O
neill	PER	PER
found	O	O
a	O	O
woman	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
flux	O	O
shut	O	O
up	O	O
with	O	O
three	O	O
men	O	O
neeld	PER	PER
found	O	O
the	O	O
prisoners	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
boro	LOC	O
compter	LOC	O
ragged	O	O
starving	O	O
and	O	O
dirty	O	O
i	O	O
come	O	O
now	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
debtors	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
they	O	O
occupied	O	O
were	O	O
divided	O	O
as	O	O
i	O	O
have	O	O
said	O	O
into	O	O
three	O	O
principal	O	O
divisions	O	O
this	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
reprehensible	O	O
claim	O	O
for	O	O
garnish	O	O
which	O	O
had	O	O
already	O	O
been	O	O
abolished	O	O
in	O	O
all	O	O
well	O	O
-	O	O
conducted	O	O
prisons	O	O
but	O	O
which	O	O
still	O	O
was	O	O
demanded	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
on	O	O
the	O	O
master	O	O
side	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
13	O	O
and	O	O
4	O	O
pints	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
gallon	O	O
of	O	O
beer	O	O
on	O	O
entrance	O	O
although	O	O
mr	O	O
newman	PER	PER
and	O	O
gave	O	O
the	O	O
garnish	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
common	O	O
side	O	O
at	O	O
that	O	O
some	O	O
which	O	O
is	O	O
5	O	O
shillings	O	O
more	O	O
than	O	O
mr	O	O
neeld	PER	PER
says	O	O
was	O	O
extorted	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
common	O	O
side	O	O
there	O	O
was	O	O
this	O	O
much	O	O
honest	O	O
forbearance	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
in	O	O
these	O	O
days	O	O
notably	O	O
as	O	O
when	O	O
numbers	O	O
filled	O	O
new	LOC	O
gate	LOC	O
in	O	O
anticipation	O	O
of	O	O
lord	O	O
reds	PER	PER
dale	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
bill	O	O
for	O	O
insolvent	O	O
debtors	O	O
the	O	O
chronicles	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
nougat	O	ORG
volume	O	O
2	O	O
by	O	O
arthur	PER	PER
griffiths	PER	PER
section	O	O
v	O	O
newgate	LOC	ORG
down	O	O
to	O	O
18	O	O
18	O	O
part	O	O
2	O	O
enough	O	O
has	O	O
been	O	O
said	O	O
probably	O	O
to	O	O
prove	O	O
that	O	O
there	O	O
was	O	O
room	O	O
for	O	O
improvement	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
condition	O	O
and	O	O
treatment	O	O
of	O	O
debtors	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
prisons	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
is	O	O
gradually	O	O
was	O	O
forced	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
consciousness	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
corporation	O	O
authority	O	O
was	O	O
given	O	O
to	O	O
raise	O	O
money	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
orphans	O	O
fund	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
extent	O	O
of	O	O
90000	O	O
lb	O	O
a	O	O
site	O	O
was	O	O
purchased	O	O
between	O	O
red	LOC	LOC
lion	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
a	O	O
new	O	O
prison	O	O
plan	O	O
which	O	O
would	O	O
accommodate	O	O
the	O	O
inmates	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
three	O	O
comforters	O	O
ludgate	LOC	O
notes	O	O
for	O	O
street	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
poultry	O	O
or	O	O
about	O	O
476	O	O
and	O	O
all	O	O
and	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
not	O	O
ready	O	O
to	O	O
relieve	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
till	O	O
late	O	O
in	O	O
1815	O	O
could	O	O
not	O	O
be	O	O
carried	O	O
out	O	O
till	O	O
then	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
feared	O	O
that	O	O
long	O	O
after	O	O
the	O	O
opening	O	O
of	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
newgate	ORG	O
continued	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
a	O	O
reproach	O	O
to	O	O
those	O	O
responsible	O	O
for	O	O
its	O	O
management	O	O
bypass	O	O
now	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
criminal	O	O
side	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
consisted	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
six	O	O
quarters	O	O
or	O	O
yards	O	O
already	O	O
enumerated	O	O
and	O	O
describe	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
heterogeneous	O	O
society	O	O
were	O	O
also	O	O
thrown	O	O
the	O	O
unfortunate	O	O
journalists	O	O
to	O	O
whom	O	O
i	O	O
have	O	O
already	O	O
referred	O	O
and	O	O
on	O	O
whom	O	O
imprisonment	O	O
in	O	O
you	O	O
gay	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
particularly	O	O
recommended	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
committee	O	ORG
on	O	O
jails	O	O
in	O	O
1814	O	O
the	O	O
honorable	O	O
hg	PER	PER
bennett	PER	PER
who	O	O
visited	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
gate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1817	O	O
saw	O	O
in	O	O
one	O	O
yard	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
total	O	O
of	O	O
72	O	O
prisoners	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
benes	PER	PER
refers	O	O
to	O	O
a	O	O
gentleman	O	O
confined	O	O
for	O	O
want	O	O
of	O	O
bail	O	O
who	O	O
occupied	O	O
a	O	O
room	O	O
with	O	O
five	O	O
others	O	O
quote	O	O
a	O	O
common	O	O
-	O	O
size	O	O
man	O	O
says	O	O
the	O	O
keeper	O	O
mr	O	O
newman	PER	PER
concern	O	O
in	O	O
19in	O	O
and	O	O
quote	O	O
these	O	O
often	O	O
remained	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
6	O	O
months	O	O
sometimes	O	O
a	O	O
year	O	O
in	O	O
some	O	O
cases	O	O
longer	O	O
mr	O	O
newman	PER	PER
admitted	O	O
that	O	O
she	O	O
had	O	O
petitioned	O	O
that	O	O
certain	O	O
trustee	O	O
men	O	O
might	O	O
be	O	O
left	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
bennet	PER	PER
mentions	O	O
also	O	O
the	O	O
case	O	O
of	O	O
young	O	O
men	O	O
have	O	O
better	O	O
stamp	O	O
clarkson	O	LOC
city	O	O
offices	O	O
and	O	O
youths	O	O
of	O	O
good	O	O
parentage	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
in	O	O
the	O	O
work	O	O
already	O	O
quoted	O	O
instances	O	O
another	O	O
grievous	O	O
case	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
horrors	O	O
of	O	O
indiscriminate	O	O
association	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
having	O	O
been	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
clerkenwell	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
was	O	O
sent	O	O
on	O	O
to	O	O
you	O	O
guys	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
coach	O	O
handcuffed	O	O
to	O	O
a	O	O
noted	O	O
house	O	O
breaker	O	O
was	O	O
afterwards	O	O
cast	O	O
for	O	O
death	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
night	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
the	O	O
subsequent	O	O
fortnight	O	O
his	O	O
wife	O	O
visited	O	O
him	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
a	O	O
pitiable	O	O
account	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
state	O	O
in	O	O
which	O	O
she	O	O
found	O	O
her	O	O
husband	O	O
the	O	O
fee	O	O
for	O	O
admission	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
stateside	ORG	O
as	O	O
fixed	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
table	O	O
of	O	O
fees	O	O
was	O	O
3	O	O
guineas	O	O
but	O	O
mr	O	O
newman	PER	PER
declared	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
never	O	O
took	O	O
more	O	O
than	O	O
two	O	O
a	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
lundy	PER	PER
charged	O	O
with	O	O
forgery	O	O
was	O	O
us	O	O
accommodated	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
stateside	O	O
for	O	O
upwards	O	O
of	O	O
five	O	O
years	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
davidson	PER	PER
sent	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
embezzlement	O	O
and	O	O
whose	O	O
case	O	O
is	O	O
given	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
preceding	O	O
chapter	O	O
was	O	O
accommodated	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
room	O	O
in	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
newman	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
house	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
extravagant	O	O
rental	O	O
of	O	O
13	O	O
guineas	O	O
per	O	O
week	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
cabot	PER	PER
was	O	O
also	O	O
a	O	O
larger	O	O
of	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
newman	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
and	O	O
so	O	O
were	O	O
any	O	O
members	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
aristocracy	O	O
if	O	O
they	O	O
happened	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
in	O	O
funds	O	O
among	O	O
whom	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
marquis	O	O
of	O	O
slego	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1811	O	O
which	O	O
will	O	O
deal	O	O
with	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
fries	PER	PER
philanthropic	O	O
exertions	O	O
at	O	O
this	O	O
.	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
particular	O	O
part	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prison	O	O
once	O	O
during	O	O
the	O	O
long	O	O
elness	O	O
of	O	O
george	PER	PER
the	O	O
third	O	O
as	O	O
many	O	O
as	O	O
100	O	O
were	O	O
there	O	O
waiting	O	O
the	O	O
report	O	O
as	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
called	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
bennett	PER	PER
speaks	O	O
of	O	O
38	O	O
capital	O	O
convicts	O	O
he	O	O
found	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
press	O	O
yard	O	O
in	O	O
february	O	O
1817	O	O
these	O	O
capital	O	O
convict	O	O
says	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
bennet	PER	PER
quote	O	O
lessons	O	O
the	O	O
ennui	O	O
and	O	O
despair	O	O
of	O	O
their	O	O
situation	O	O
by	O	O
unbecoming	O	O
merriment	O	O
i	O	O
saw	O	O
cashman	PER	PER
a	O	O
few	O	O
hours	O	O
before	O	O
his	O	O
execution	O	O
smoking	O	O
and	O	O
drinking	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
utmost	O	O
unconcerned	O	O
and	O	O
indifference	O	O
end	O	O
quote	O	O
will	O	O
mike	PER	PER
mr	O	O
.	O	O
bennett	PER	PER
right	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
condition	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
condemned	O	O
side	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
prominent	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
many	O	O
-	O	O
fold	O	O
evils	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
prison	O	O
system	O	O
of	O	O
nougat	O	O
such	O	O
as	O	O
measures	O	O
virtual	O	ORG
corn	LOC	ORG
hill	LOC	O
and	O	O
messrs	O	O
leach	PER	PER
and	O	ORG
dollemore	PER	PER
of	O	O
ludgate	LOC	LOC
hill	LOC	LOC
preparatory	O	O
to	O	O
their	O	O
appearance	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
old	LOC	LOC
bailey	LOC	LOC
irons	O	O
were	O	O
seldom	O	O
removed	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
convicted	O	O
until	O	O
discharge	O	O
any	O	O
reputed	O	O
and	O	O
indeed	O	O
any	O	O
real	O	O
wife	O	O
might	O	O
spend	O	O
the	O	O
night	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
if	O	O
she	O	O
would	O	O
pay	O	O
this	O	O
chilling	O	O
c	O	O
commonly	O	O
known	O	O
as	O	O
the	O	O
bad	O	O
money	O	O
check	O	O
the	O	O
open	O	O
house	O	O
so	O	O
to	O	O
speak	O	O
and	O	O
entertained	O	O
daily	O	O
within	O	O
the	O	O
walls	O	O
a	O	O
select	O	O
party	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
noted	O	O
thieves	O	O
in	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
going	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
facility	O	O
of	O	O
intercourse	O	O
between	O	O
inside	O	O
and	O	O
outside	O	O
many	O	O
crimes	O	O
were	O	O
doubtless	O	O
hacked	O	O
in	O	O
uk	LOC	LOC
why	O	O
did	O	O
leave	O	O
says	O	O
mr	O	O
bennett	PER	PER
in	O	O
the	O	O
letter	O	O
already	O	O
largely	O	O
quoted	O	O
but	O	O
there	O	O
is	O	O
no	O	O
place	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
metropolis	O	O
where	O	O
more	O	O
crimes	O	O
are	O	O
projected	O	O
or	O	O
where	O	O
stolen	O	O
property	O	O
is	O	O
more	O	O
secreted	O	O
although	O	O
attempted	O	O
partially	O	O
at	O	O
bridewell	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
more	O	O
systematically	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
new	O	O
millbank	LOC	O
penitentiary	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
not	O	O
strange	O	O
therefore	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
inmates	O	O
of	O	O
nougat	O	O
should	O	O
turn	O	O
their	O	O
unoccupied	O	O
brains	O	O
and	O	O
idle	O	O
hands	O	O
to	O	O
all	O	O
manner	O	O
of	O	O
mischief	O	O
the	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
committee	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
painted	O	O
so	O	O
black	O	O
a	O	O
picture	O	O
of	O	O
new	O	O
gays	O	O
has	O	O
been	O	O
conducted	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
corporation	O	O
were	O	O
roused	O	O
in	O	O
very	O	O
shame	O	O
court	ORG	O
of	ORG	O
aldermen	ORG	O
appointed	O	O
a	O	O
committee	O	O
of	O	O
its	O	O
own	O	O
body	O	O
assisted	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
town	O	O
clock	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
city	O	O
surveyor	O	O
sun	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
architect	O	O
send	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
addison	PER	PER
keeper	O	O
of	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
gate	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
make	O	O
a	O	O
visitation	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
supposed	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
the	O	O
best	O	O
managed	O	O
including	O	O
those	O	O
of	O	O
petworth	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
gloucester	LOC	LOC
also	O	O
to	O	O
make	O	O
such	O	O
proposals	O	O
as	O	O
might	O	O
appear	O	O
salutary	O	O
and	O	O
calculated	O	O
to	O	O
improve	O	O
new	O	O
gays	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
rest	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
jails	O	O
have	O	O
they	O	O
been	O	O
accepted	O	O
in	O	O
their	O	O
entirety	O	O
little	O	O
salt	O	O
couldn	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
future	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
found	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
managers	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	ORG	ORG
the	O	O
committee	ORG	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
deny	O	O
the	O	O
superior	O	O
advantages	O	O
offered	O	O
by	O	O
such	O	O
prisons	O	O
as	O	O
gloucester	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
petworth	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
quote	O	O
it	O	O
would	O	O
cover	O	O
some	O	O
30	O	O
acres	O	O
and	O	O
cost	O	O
a	O	O
great	O	O
deal	O	O
more	O	O
than	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
example	O	O
of	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
before	O	O
it	O	O
the	O	O
committee	O	O
does	O	O
not	O	O
seem	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
yet	O	O
understood	O	O
that	O	O
new	ORG	O
gate	ORG	O
could	O	O
be	O	O
only	O	O
and	O	O
properly	O	O
replaced	O	O
buy	O	O
a	O	O
new	O	O
jail	O	O
built	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
outskirts	O	O
as	O	O
holloway	PER	PER
eventually	O	O
was	O	O
and	O	O
committed	O	O
itself	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
altogether	O	O
counter	O	O
i	O	O
'	O	O
m	O	O
checked	O	O
in	O	O
its	O	O
efforts	O	O
towards	O	O
reform	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
prohibitory	O	O
costliness	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
land	O	O
about	O	O
nougat	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
very	O	O
desirable	O	O
that	O	O
there	O	O
should	O	O
be	O	O
a	O	O
more	O	O
speedy	O	O
removal	O	O
of	O	O
transports	O	O
from	O	O
you	O	O
gate	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
ships	O	O
again	O	O
there	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
new	O	O
millbank	LOC	O
penitentiary	O	O
now	O	O
ready	O	O
for	O	O
occupation	O	O
why	O	O
not	O	O
relieving	O	O
you	O	O
gate	O	O
more	O	O
largely	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
superior	O	O
accommodation	O	O
which	O	O
build	O	O
bank	ORG	O
offer	O	O
chronicles	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
new	LOC	ORG
gate	LOC	ORG
volume	O	O
2	O	O
by	O	O
arthur	PER	PER
griffith	PER	PER
section	O	O
7	O	O
the	O	O
beginnings	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
reform	O	O
while	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
fry	PER	PER
was	O	O
diligently	O	O
engaged	O	O
upon	O	O
her	O	O
self	O	O
-	O	O
imposed	O	O
task	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
howard	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
energy	O	O
and	O	O
devotion	O	O
were	O	O
rewarded	O	O
by	O	O
lively	O	O
sympathy	O	O
but	O	O
the	O	O
desire	O	O
to	O	O
improve	O	O
which	O	O
followed	O	O
his	O	O
exposures	O	O
was	O	O
but	O	O
short	O	O
-	O	O
lived	O	O
mister	O	O
kneeled	PER	O
a	O	O
second	O	O
howard	PER	PER
mr	O	O
nield	PER	PER
was	O	O
compelled	O	O
to	O	O
admit	O	O
in	O	O
1812	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
reformation	O	O
produced	O	O
by	O	O
howard	PER	PER
i	O	O
have	O	O
shown	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
previous	O	O
chapter	O	O
what	O	O
new	LOC	O
gate	LOC	O
was	O	O
at	O	O
this	O	O
.	O	O
despite	O	O
a	O	O
vast	O	O
expenditure	O	O
and	O	O
boasted	O	O
efforts	O	O
to	O	O
introduce	O	O
reforms	O	O
watching	O	O
son	O	O
the	O	O
duke	O	PER
of	O	O
gloucester	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
the	O	O
patron	O	O
among	O	O
the	O	O
vice	O	O
presidents	O	O
were	O	O
many	O	O
great	O	O
peers	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
realm	O	O
several	O	O
bishops	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
number	O	O
of	O	O
members	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
including	O	O
mr	O	O
manners	PER	PER
sutton	PER	PER
sturgis	PER	PER
born	O	O
sir	O	O
james	PER	PER
mcintosh	PER	PER
sir	O	O
james	PER	PER
scarlet	PER	PER
wilberforce	PER	PER
one	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
moving	O	O
spirits	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
honorable	O	O
hg	PER	PER
bennett	PER	PER
auntie	PER	O
whose	O	O
vigorous	O	O
protests	O	O
against	O	O
the	O	O
lamentable	O	O
condition	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
have	O	O
already	O	O
been	O	O
recorded	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
fry	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
brother	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
samuel	PER	PER
hoare	PER	PER
junior	O	PER
was	O	O
chairman	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
committee	O	O
on	O	O
which	O	O
also	O	O
served	O	O
many	O	O
noted	O	O
members	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
society	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
friends	ORG	ORG
mr	O	O
.	O	O
green	PER	PER
with	O	O
stir	O	PER
-	O	PER
fry	O	PER
mizer	O	PER
'	O	PER
s	O	PER
forester	PER	PER
and	O	O
mr	O	O
t	PER	PER
f	PER	PER
buxton	PER	PER
the	O	O
coadjutor	O	O
of	O	O
wilberforce	PER	PER
in	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
anti	O	O
-	O	O
slavery	O	O
struggle	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
had	O	O
already	O	O
been	O	O
associated	O	O
with	O	O
misses	O	O
frying	PER	O
and	O	O
you	O	O
get	O	O
visitation	O	O
and	O	O
his	O	O
attention	O	O
had	O	O
this	O	O
been	O	O
drawn	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
neglected	O	O
state	O	O
of	O	O
english	O	O
prisons	O	O
when	O	O
in	O	O
belgium	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
had	O	O
examined	O	O
with	O	O
great	O	O
satisfaction	O	O
the	O	O
admirable	O	O
management	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
maison	ORG	ORG
de	ORG	ORG
force	ORG	ORG
against	O	O
which	O	O
howard	PER	PER
had	O	O
eulogized	O	O
some	O	O
40	O	O
years	O	O
before	O	O
richard	PER	PER
buxton	PER	PER
small	O	O
work	O	O
on	O	O
prison	O	O
discipline	O	O
avenue	O	O
aspect	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
question	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
so	O	O
much	O	O
at	O	O
heart	O	O
they	O	O
had	O	O
a	O	O
right	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
firmed	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
employed	O	O
in	O	O
their	O	O
own	O	O
crafts	O	O
provided	O	O
it	O	O
could	O	O
be	O	O
safely	O	O
followed	O	O
in	O	O
prison	O	O
the	O	O
convicted	O	O
delinquent	O	O
has	O	O
his	O	O
right	O	O
said	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
authoritatively	O	O
as	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
pointed	O	O
out	O	O
many	O	O
old	O	O
acts	O	O
of	O	O
parliament	O	O
designed	O	O
to	O	O
protect	O	O
the	O	O
prisoner	O	O
we	O	O
'	O	O
re	O	O
still	O	O
in	O	O
full	O	O
force	O	O
as	O	O
far	O	O
back	O	O
is	O	O
the	O	O
reign	O	O
of	O	O
charles	PER	PER
ii	O	PER
a	O	O
law	O	O
was	O	O
passed	O	O
to	O	O
clearing	O	O
the	O	O
sufficient	O	O
provision	O	O
should	O	O
be	O	O
made	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
relief	O	O
and	O	O
setting	O	O
on	O	O
work	O	O
again	O	O
the	O	O
22	O	O
charles	PER	PER
ii	O	PER
c20	O	O
order	O	O
the	O	O
jailer	O	O
to	O	O
keep	O	O
felons	O	O
and	O	O
debtors	O	O
separate	O	O
and	O	O
apart	O	O
from	O	O
one	O	O
another	O	O
how	O	O
much	O	O
later	O	O
act	O	O
the	O	O
14	O	O
george	PER	PER
the	O	O
third	O	O
c59	O	O
1774	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
contemporaneous	O	O
with	O	O
howard	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
first	O	O
journeys	O	O
laid	O	O
down	O	O
precise	O	O
rules	O	O
as	O	O
regards	O	O
cleanliness	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
proper	O	O
supply	O	O
of	O	O
space	O	O
&	O	O
air	O	O
531	O	O
george	PER	PER
the	O	O
third	O	O
c	O	O
-	O	O
46	O	O
s5	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
important	O	O
jail	O	O
active	O	O
satterlee	O	LOC
.	O	O
however	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
24	O	O
george	PER	LOC
the	O	O
third	O	O
c	O	O
-	O	O
54	O	O
s4	O	O
1784	O	O
in	O	O
an	O	O
early	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	ORG
discipline	ORG	ORG
improvement	ORG	ORG
society	ORG	ORG
in	O	O
1818	O	O
out	O	O
of	O	O
518	O	O
prisons	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
kingdom	LOC	LOC
specify	O	O
more	O	O
particularly	O	O
one	O	O
or	O	O
two	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
worst	O	O
it	O	O
may	O	O
be	O	O
mentioned	O	O
that	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
boro	LOC	O
comforter	LOC	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
who	O	O
found	O	O
this	O	O
declared	O	O
that	O	O
it	O	O
seemed	O	O
physically	O	O
impossible	O	O
but	O	O
he	O	O
was	O	O
assured	O	O
that	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
true	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
turnkey	O	O
told	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
that	O	O
the	O	O
smell	O	O
on	O	O
first	O	O
opening	O	O
the	O	O
door	O	O
with	O	O
enough	O	O
to	O	O
knock	O	O
down	O	O
a	O	O
horse	O	O
gildford	LOC	LOC
prison	O	O
which	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
also	O	O
visited	O	O
in	O	O
1818	O	O
matters	O	O
were	O	O
on	O	O
much	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
footing	O	O
at	O	O
st	LOC	LOC
albans	LOC	LOC
they	O	O
were	O	O
far	O	O
worse	O	O
at	O	O
bristol	LOC	LOC
although	O	O
it	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
visit	O	O
a	O	O
new	O	O
jail	O	O
was	O	O
in	O	O
process	O	O
of	O	O
erection	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
step	O	O
towards	O	O
reform	O	O
since	O	O
howard	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
visitation	O	O
in	O	O
1774	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
crowd	O	O
all	O	O
of	O	O
them	O	O
persons	O	O
who	O	O
had	O	O
no	O	O
other	O	O
avocation	O	O
or	O	O
mode	O	O
of	O	O
livelihood	O	O
but	O	O
leaving	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
counted	O	O
11	O	O
children	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
scene	O	O
of	O	O
infertile	O	O
passions	O	O
and	O	O
distressed	O	O
says	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
which	O	O
few	O	O
have	O	O
imagination	O	O
sufficient	O	O
to	O	O
picture	O	O
consignment	O	O
for	O	O
12	O	O
months	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
bristol	LOC	LOC
jail	O	O
was	O	O
counted	O	O
a	O	O
punishment	O	O
equivalent	O	O
to	O	O
seven	O	O
years	O	O
transportation	O	O
already	O	O
as	O	O
early	O	O
as	O	O
1818	O	O
prison	O	O
existed	O	O
at	O	O
bury	LOC	LOC
st	LOC	LOC
edmunds	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
model	O	O
for	O	O
imitation	O	O
to	O	O
others	O	O
at	O	O
that	O	O
time	O	O
another	O	O
jail	O	O
that	O	O
appeal	O	O
chester	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
also	O	O
worthy	O	O
of	O	O
all	O	O
commendation	O	O
it	O	O
exhibited	O	O
all	O	O
the	O	O
good	O	O
points	O	O
of	O	O
that	O	O
it	O	O
very	O	O
ilchester	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
rule	O	O
of	O	O
employment	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
carried	O	O
further	O	O
the	O	O
system	O	O
not	O	O
adopted	O	O
generally	O	O
till	O	O
nearly	O	O
half	O	O
a	O	O
century	O	O
later	O	O
had	O	O
already	O	O
prevail	O	O
that	O	O
bill	PER	PER
chester	PER	PER
compared	O	O
with	O	O
those	O	O
highly	O	O
meritorious	O	O
institutions	O	O
newgate	ORG	ORG
still	O	O
showed	O	O
but	O	O
badly	O	O
mainly	O	O
through	O	O
the	O	O
exertions	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
new	O	O
governor	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
brown	PER	PER
who	O	O
succeeded	O	O
mr	O	O
newman	PER	PER
at	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1817	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
brown	PER	PER
confidently	O	O
asserted	O	O
that	O	O
no	O	O
jail	O	O
in	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
now	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
brown	PER	PER
also	O	O
much	O	O
to	O	O
his	O	O
own	O	O
credit	O	O
.	O	O
the	O	O
practice	O	O
of	O	O
ironing	O	O
all	O	O
prisoners	O	O
as	O	O
a	O	O
matter	O	O
of	O	O
course	O	O
in	O	O
1818	O	O
prisoners	O	O
awaiting	O	O
trial	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
relieved	O	O
from	O	O
this	O	O
illegal	O	O
infliction	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
mentions	O	O
the	O	O
case	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
boy	O	O
whose	O	O
apparent	O	O
innocence	O	O
and	O	O
artlessness	O	O
had	O	O
attracted	O	O
his	O	O
attention	O	O
he	O	O
left	O	O
newgate	ORG	ORG
charlie	PER	ORG
corrupted	O	O
after	O	O
lapsing	O	O
into	O	O
crime	O	O
soon	O	O
returned	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
very	O	O
different	O	O
character	O	O
some	O	O
attempt	O	O
was	O	O
made	O	O
to	O	O
reduce	O	O
the	O	O
overcrowding	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
recommendation	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
committee	O	O
of	O	O
1818	O	O
but	O	O
this	O	O
applied	O	O
only	O	O
a	O	O
partial	O	O
remedy	O	O
just	O	O
disposing	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
objection	O	O
so	O	O
long	O	O
ranged	O	O
against	O	O
the	O	O
industrial	O	O
employment	O	O
of	O	O
prisoners	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
as	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
discipline	ORG	O
society	ORG	ORG
pertinently	O	O
observed	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
report	O	O
dated	O	O
1820	O	O
the	O	O
chronicles	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
nougat	O	O
volume	O	O
2	O	O
by	O	O
arthur	PER	PER
griffith	PER	PER
section	O	O
8	O	O
the	O	O
beginnings	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
reform	O	O
newgate	ORG	LOC
prisoners	O	O
were	O	O
the	O	O
victims	O	O
to	O	O
another	O	O
most	O	O
objectionable	O	O
practice	O	O
which	O	O
obtained	O	O
all	O	O
over	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
even	O	O
though	O	O
they	O	O
were	O	O
not	O	O
certain	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
favor	O	O
for	O	O
i	O	O
find	O	O
reference	O	O
to	O	O
a	O	O
decent	O	O
and	O	O
respectable	O	O
woman	O	O
sent	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
one	O	O
smug	O	O
alderman	O	O
a	O	O
member	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
sneered	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
ultra	O	O
philanthropy	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
champions	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
improvement	O	O
our	O	O
prisoners	O	O
have	O	O
all	O	O
that	O	O
prisoners	O	O
ought	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
without	O	O
gentlemen	O	O
think	O	O
they	O	O
ought	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
indulged	O	O
with	O	O
turkey	LOC	LOC
carpets	O	O
the	O	O
society	ORG	ORG
for	ORG	ORG
the	ORG	ORG
improvement	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
prison	ORG	O
discipline	ORG	O
was	O	O
taxed	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
desire	O	O
to	O	O
introduce	O	O
a	O	O
system	O	O
an	O	O
imputation	O	O
which	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
indignantly	O	O
and	O	O
very	O	O
justly	O	O
repudiated	O	O
the	O	O
statement	O	O
being	O	O
as	O	O
they	O	O
said	O	O
among	O	O
those	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
found	O	O
a	O	O
raid	O	O
against	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
sidney	PER	PER
smith	PER	PER
admitting	O	O
the	O	O
good	O	O
intentions	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
he	O	O
condemned	O	O
there	O	O
ultra	O	O
humanitarianism	O	O
as	O	O
misplaced	O	O
he	O	O
took	O	O
exception	O	O
to	O	O
various	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
proposals	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
he	O	O
thought	O	O
they	O	O
linked	O	O
too	O	O
much	O	O
to	O	O
a	O	O
system	O	O
of	O	O
indulgences	O	O
and	O	O
education	O	O
in	O	O
jails	O	O
society	O	O
pursuit	O	O
it	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
laudable	O	O
undertaking	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
remarkable	O	O
energy	O	O
and	O	O
great	O	O
singleness	O	O
of	O	O
purpose	O	O
a	O	O
much	O	O
-	O	O
needed	O	O
and	O	O
according	O	O
to	O	O
our	O	O
ideas	O	O
indispensable	O	O
reform	O	O
already	O	O
initiated	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
ladies	ORG	O
committee	ORG	O
at	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
good	O	O
at	O	O
tried	O	O
to	O	O
do	O	O
took	O	O
active	O	O
shape	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
establishment	O	O
of	O	O
temporary	O	O
refuges	O	O
at	O	O
hoxton	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
males	O	O
and	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
hackney	LOC	LOC
road	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
females	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
reception	O	O
of	O	O
deserving	O	O
cases	O	O
discharged	O	O
from	O	O
prison	O	O
the	O	O
governor	O	O
a	O	O
new	LOC	O
gate	LOC	O
and	O	O
other	O	O
metropolitan	O	O
prisons	O	O
had	O	O
orders	O	O
of	O	O
admission	O	O
to	O	O
this	O	O
refuge	O	O
brandon	PER	PER
moral	O	O
and	O	O
religious	O	O
duty	O	O
and	O	O
which	O	O
after	O	O
a	O	O
time	O	O
sought	O	O
to	O	O
provide	O	O
them	O	O
with	O	O
suitable	O	O
situations	O	O
was	O	O
supported	O	O
entirely	O	O
out	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
funds	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
another	O	O
point	O	O
to	O	O
which	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
devoted	O	O
infinite	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
preparation	O	O
of	O	O
plans	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
guidance	O	O
of	O	O
architects	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
construction	O	O
of	O	O
prisons	O	O
a	O	O
very	O	O
valuable	O	O
volume	O	O
published	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
or	O	O
a	O	O
dungeon	O	O
above	O	O
or	O	O
below	O	O
the	O	O
gate	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
town	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
attempts	O	O
at	O	O
systematic	O	O
reconstruction	O	O
carryout	O	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
advice	O	O
and	O	O
supervision	O	O
of	O	O
howard	PER	PER
was	O	O
introduced	O	O
as	O	O
early	O	O
as	O	O
1790	O	O
by	O	O
mr	O	O
blackburn	PER	PER
the	O	O
society	ORG	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
limit	O	O
its	O	O
remarks	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
description	O	O
of	O	O
what	O	O
had	O	O
already	O	O
been	O	O
done	O	O
the	O	O
new	O	O
jails	O	O
as	O	O
howard	PER	PER
says	O	O
having	O	O
pompous	O	O
fronts	O	O
appear	O	O
like	O	O
palaces	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
lower	O	O
class	O	O
of	O	O
people	O	O
and	O	O
many	O	O
persons	O	O
are	O	O
against	O	O
them	O	O
on	O	O
this	O	O
account	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
society	ORG	O
reproves	O	O
the	O	O
misdirected	O	O
efforts	O	O
of	O	O
ambitious	O	O
architect	O	O
to	O	O
buy	O	O
a	O	O
lavish	O	O
an	O	O
improvident	O	O
expenditure	O	O
of	O	O
public	O	O
money	O	O
these	O	O
are	O	O
principles	O	O
fully	O	O
recognized	O	O
nowadays	O	O
and	O	O
it	O	O
may	O	O
fairly	O	O
be	O	O
conceded	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
discipline	ORG	O
society	ORG	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
ideal	O	O
after	O	O
a	O	O
few	O	O
years	O	O
of	O	O
active	O	O
exertion	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
was	O	O
rewarded	O	O
by	O	O
fresh	O	O
legislation	O	O
to	O	O
its	O	O
efforts	O	O
and	O	O
their	O	O
effect	O	O
upon	O	O
parliament	ORG	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
public	O	O
mind	O	O
we	O	O
must	O	O
attribute	O	O
the	O	O
new	O	O
jail	O	O
acts	O	O
of	O	O
for	O	O
george	PER	PER
the	O	O
4th	O	O
cap	O	O
64	O	O
and	O	O
5	O	O
george	PER	PER
the	O	O
fourth	O	O
cap	O	O
85	O	O
classification	O	O
was	O	O
insisted	O	O
upon	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
manner	O	O
laid	O	O
down	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
24	O	O
george	PER	O
the	O	O
third	O	O
cat	O	O
54	O	O
the	O	O
second	O	O
act	O	O
passed	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
following	O	O
year	O	O
enlarged	O	O
and	O	O
amended	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
and	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
time	O	O
gave	O	O
powers	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
house	O	O
the	O	O
promulgation	O	O
of	O	O
these	O	O
to	O	O
jail	O	O
acts	O	O
strengthen	O	O
the	O	O
hands	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
discipline	ORG	O
society	ORG	O
enormously	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
shrink	O	O
from	O	O
its	O	O
self	O	O
-	O	O
imposed	O	O
duty	O	O
but	O	O
continued	O	O
year	O	O
after	O	O
year	O	O
with	O	O
unflagging	O	O
energy	O	O
and	O	O
unflinching	O	O
spirit	O	O
to	O	O
watch	O	O
closely	O	O
upon	O	O
these	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
private	O	O
visitations	O	O
made	O	O
by	O	O
various	O	O
members	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
obtained	O	O
effects	O	O
tales	O	O
of	O	O
which	O	O
the	O	O
old	O	O
prison	O	O
at	O	O
reading	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
a	O	O
specimen	O	O
we	O	O
'	O	O
re	O	O
still	O	O
left	O	O
intact	O	O
numbers	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jails	O	O
were	O	O
still	O	O
on	O	O
provided	O	O
with	O	O
chaplains	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
prisoners	O	O
never	O	O
heard	O	O
divine	O	O
service	O	O
the	O	O
interior	O	O
of	O	O
one	O	O
prison	O	O
was	O	O
illuminated	O	O
throughout	O	O
with	O	O
gas	O	O
still	O	O
a	O	O
novelty	O	O
which	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
generally	O	O
adopted	O	O
in	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
only	O	O
4	O	O
years	O	O
previously	O	O
four	O	O
years	O	O
later	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
society	ORG	O
reported	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
new	O	O
prison	O	O
clerkenwell	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
had	O	O
become	O	O
the	O	O
principal	O	O
reception	O	O
jail	O	O
of	O	O
middlesex	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
so	O	O
took	O	O
all	O	O
the	O	O
untried	O	O
yet	O	O
to	O	O
clerkenwell	LOC	LOC
we	O	O
'	O	O
re	O	O
now	O	O
committed	O	O
the	O	O
juvenile	O	O
and	O	O
all	O	O
who	O	O
are	O	O
inexperienced	O	O
in	O	O
crime	O	O
mister	O	O
peel	PER	PER
who	O	O
as	O	O
home	O	O
secretary	O	O
had	O	O
charge	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
bill	O	O
which	O	O
became	O	O
the	O	O
four	O	O
george	PER	O
the	O	O
4th	O	O
tap	O	O
64	O	O
said	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
abstained	O	O
from	O	O
legislating	O	O
for	O	O
these	O	O
small	O	O
jurisdictions	O	O
on	O	O
mature	O	O
deliberation	O	O
at	O	O
this	O	O
time	O	O
there	O	O
were	O	O
in	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
170	O	O
barros	O	ORG
cities	O	O
towns	O	O
and	O	O
liberties	O	O
as	O	O
the	O	O
science	O	O
he	O	O
put	O	O
it	O	O
in	O	O
1827	O	O
the	O	O
friends	O	ORG
to	O	ORG
the	O	O
improvement	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
discipline	O	O
this	O	O
is	O	O
sorry	O	O
she	O	O
proceeded	O	O
to	O	O
support	O	O
this	O	O
indictment	O	O
by	O	O
fax	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
much	O	O
the	O	O
old	O	O
story	O	O
i	O	O
just	O	O
chillin	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
commissioners	O	O
to	O	O
inquire	O	O
into	O	O
the	O	O
state	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
municipal	O	O
corporations	O	O
in	O	O
1835	O	O
dennis	PER	PER
murder	O	O
in	O	O
marion	LOC	LOC
sure	O	O
had	O	O
besides	O	O
the	O	O
pinfold	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
stocks	O	O
or	O	O
crib	O	O
a	O	O
little	O	O
prison	O	O
clun	O	ORG
in	O	O
shropshire	LOC	LOC
had	O	O
a	O	O
lock	O	O
up	O	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
town	O	O
hall	O	O
i	O	O
in	O	O
suffolk	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
jail	O	O
was	O	O
part	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
pour	O	O
house	O	O
so	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
at	O	O
richmond	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
yorkshire	LOC	LOC
where	O	O
the	O	O
master	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
workhouse	O	O
was	O	O
also	O	O
keeper	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
godmanchester	LOC	PER
there	O	O
was	O	O
no	O	O
jail	O	O
but	O	O
cage	O	O
to	O	O
secure	O	O
prisoners	O	O
till	O	O
they	O	O
could	O	O
be	O	O
taken	O	O
before	O	O
a	O	O
magistrate	O	O
kidderminster	ORG	LOC
had	O	O
a	O	O
prison	O	O
one	O	O
dance	O	O
chill	O	O
room	O	O
walsall	LOC	ORG
and	O	O
staffordshire	LOC	ORG
newgate	LOC	PER
through	O	O
all	O	O
these	O	O
years	O	O
continue	O	O
to	O	O
buy	O	O
word	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	O
what	O	O
was	O	O
pointed	O	O
out	O	O
in	O	O
1823	O	O
that	O	O
defective	O	O
construction	O	O
must	O	O
always	O	O
bar	O	O
the	O	O
way	O	O
to	O	O
any	O	O
radical	O	O
improvement	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1824	O	O
do	O	ORG
gays	O	ORG
had	O	O
no	O	O
glass	O	O
and	O	O
its	O	O
windows	O	O
except	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
infirmary	O	O
and	O	O
one	O	O
ward	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
chapel	LOC	O
yard	O	O
there	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
diminution	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
numbers	O	O
in	O	O
custody	O	O
due	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
adoption	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
practice	O	O
of	O	O
not	O	O
committing	O	O
and	O	O
wants	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
every	O	O
offender	O	O
for	O	O
trial	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
old	LOC	O
bailey	LOC	O
in	O	O
1827	O	O
the	O	O
society	O	ORG
was	O	O
compelled	O	O
to	O	O
report	O	O
that	O	O
no	O	O
material	O	O
change	O	O
has	O	O
taken	O	O
place	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
since	O	O
the	O	O
passing	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prison	O	O
laws	O	O
idleness	O	O
was	O	O
still	O	O
the	O	O
general	O	O
rule	O	O
for	O	O
all	O	O
prisoners	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
defiance	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
law	O	O
i	O	O
shall	O	O
have	O	O
more	O	O
to	O	O
say	O	O
on	O	O
this	O	O
subject	O	O
and	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
state	O	O
of	O	O
nougat	O	O
generally	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
following	O	O
chapter	O	O
the	O	O
prison	ORG	O
society	ORG	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
relax	O	O
its	O	O
efforts	O	O
as	O	O
time	O	O
passed	O	O
but	O	O
its	O	O
leading	O	O
members	O	O
had	O	O
other	O	O
and	O	O
more	O	O
pressing	O	O
claims	O	O
upon	O	O
their	O	O
energies	O	O
mr	O	O
buxton	PER	PER
had	O	O
succeeded	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
work	O	O
which	O	O
william	PER	PER
wilberforce	PER	PER
had	O	O
commenced	O	O
and	O	O
led	O	O
the	O	O
repeated	O	O
attacks	O	O
upon	O	O
slavery	O	O
in	O	O
british	O	O
colonies	O	O
nevertheless	O	O
a	O	O
committee	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
was	O	O
appointed	O	O
in	O	O
1831	O	O
to	O	O
report	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
whole	O	O
system	O	O
of	O	O
secondary	O	O
punishments	O	O
this	O	O
committee	O	O
anniversary	O	O
strongly	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
system	O	O
in	O	O
force	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
metropolitan	O	O
jails	O	O
and	O	O
more	O	O
especially	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
condition	O	O
of	O	O
nougat	O	O
mister	O	O
samuel	PER	PER
hoare	PER	PER
was	O	O
examined	O	O
by	O	O
this	O	O
committee	O	O
i	O	O
stated	O	O
that	O	O
in	O	O
his	O	O
opinion	O	O
new	ORG	LOC
gate	ORG	LOC
as	O	O
the	O	O
common	O	O
jail	O	O
of	O	O
middlesex	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
wholly	O	O
inadequate	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
proper	O	O
confinement	O	O
of	O	O
its	O	O
prisoners	O	O
prisoners	O	O
were	O	O
crowded	O	O
together	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
jail	O	O
contrary	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
requirements	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
for	O	O
george	PER	O
the	O	O
4th	O	O
again	O	O
in	O	O
1835	O	O
prisons	O	O
and	O	O
their	O	O
inmates	O	O
became	O	O
once	O	O
more	O	O
the	O	O
care	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
senate	ORG	ORG
and	O	O
the	O	O
subject	O	O
was	O	O
taken	O	O
up	O	O
this	O	O
time	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
lords	ORG	ORG
the	O	O
committee	O	O
was	O	O
appointed	O	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
presidency	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
duke	O	PER
of	O	PER
richmond	LOC	PER
to	O	O
inquire	O	O
into	O	O
and	O	O
report	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
several	O	O
jails	O	O
and	O	O
houses	O	O
of	O	O
correction	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
county	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
cities	O	O
and	O	O
corporate	O	O
towns	O	O
within	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
wales	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
lords	ORG	ORG
committee	ORG	ORG
fully	O	O
recognize	O	O
the	O	O
painful	O	O
fact	O	O
still	O	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
burrow	ORG	O
corporations	ORG	O
the	O	O
commons	ORG	ORG
committee	ORG	O
gave	O	O
it	O	O
as	O	O
their	O	O
opinion	O	O
that	O	O
they	O	O
were	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
deplorable	O	O
state	O	O
in	O	O
some	O	O
large	O	O
towns	O	O
as	O	O
at	O	O
berwick	LOC	LOC
on	O	O
tweed	O	LOC
southampton	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
south	LOC	LOC
work	LOC	LOC
they	O	O
the	O	O
prisons	O	O
are	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
very	O	O
discreditable	O	O
condition	O	O
the	O	O
lords	ORG	ORG
committee	ORG	ORG
on	ORG	ORG
jails	ORG	O
were	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
opinion	O	O
that	O	O
considered	O	O
the	O	O
prisons	O	O
under	O	O
corporate	O	O
or	O	O
peculiar	O	O
jurisdiction	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
very	O	O
unsatisfactory	O	O
condition	O	O
the	O	O
whole	O	O
question	O	O
was	O	O
again	O	O
dealt	O	O
with	O	O
in	O	O
lord	O	O
john	PER	PER
russell	PER	PER
bill	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
reform	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
municipal	ORG	O
corporations	ORG	O
and	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
more	O	O
liberal	O	O
election	O	O
of	O	O
town	O	O
councillors	O	O
the	O	O
chronicles	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
nougat	O	O
volume	O	O
2	O	O
by	O	O
arthur	PER	PER
griffiths	PER	PER
section	O	O
9	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
inspector	O	O
of	O	O
prisons	O	O
newgate	LOC	O
has	O	O
remained	O	O
rather	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
background	O	O
while	O	O
the	O	O
whole	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
jails	O	O
as	O	O
a	O	O
body	O	O
wear	O	O
under	O	O
discussion	O	O
i	O	O
shall	O	O
not	O	O
return	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
jail	O	O
if	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
give	O	O
a	O	O
more	O	O
detailed	O	O
account	O	O
of	O	O
its	O	O
condition	O	O
and	O	O
inner	O	O
life	O	O
these	O	O
gentlemen	O	O
were	O	O
appointed	O	O
in	O	O
october	O	O
1835	O	O
owing	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
strong	O	O
representations	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
lords	ORG	ORG
committee	ORG	O
mister	O	O
samuel	PER	PER
hoare	PER	PER
when	O	O
examined	O	O
considered	O	O
it	O	O
indispensably	O	O
necessary	O	O
to	O	O
carry	O	O
out	O	O
whatever	O	O
system	O	O
might	O	O
be	O	O
established	O	O
sir	O	O
frederick	PER	PER
roe	PER	PER
was	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
opinion	O	O
as	O	O
regards	O	O
the	O	O
appointment	O	O
but	O	O
he	O	O
would	O	O
give	O	O
the	O	O
inspectors	O	O
the	O	O
power	O	O
of	O	O
acting	O	O
as	O	O
well	O	O
as	O	O
reporting	O	O
with	O	O
those	O	O
who	O	O
made	O	O
the	O	O
selection	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
inspectors	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
two	O	O
gentlemen	O	O
appointed	O	O
we	O	O
'	O	O
re	O	O
probably	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
fitted	O	O
in	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
be	O	O
so	O	O
employed	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
william	PER	PER
crawford	PER	PER
the	O	O
other	O	O
the	O	O
reverend	O	O
whitworth	PER	PER
russell	PER	PER
william	PER	PER
crawford	PER	PER
had	O	O
been	O	O
one	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
promoters	O	O
and	O	O
managers	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
philanthropic	ORG	O
societies	ORG	O
farm	O	O
school	O	O
later	O	O
on	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
devoted	O	O
himself	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
personal	O	O
investigation	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prisons	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
at	O	O
that	O	O
time	O	O
the	O	O
mild	O	O
and	O	O
intelligent	O	O
prison	O	O
discipline	O	O
in	O	O
force	O	O
in	O	O
pennsylvania	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
legacy	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
old	O	O
quaker	O	O
immigrants	O	O
i	O	O
'	O	O
ve	O	O
made	O	O
such	O	O
prisons	O	O
at	O	O
auburn	LOC	LOC
a	O	O
model	O	O
for	O	O
imitation	O	O
france	LOC	LOC
had	O	O
sent	O	O
misuse	O	O
beaumont	PER	PER
and	O	O
de	PER	PER
tocqueville	PER	PER
who	O	O
subsequently	O	O
published	O	O
several	O	O
interesting	O	O
works	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
subject	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
represented	O	O
by	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
crawford	PER	PER
and	O	O
the	O	O
result	O	O
of	O	O
his	O	O
inquiry	O	O
was	O	O
given	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
public	O	O
as	O	O
an	O	O
appendix	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
report	O	O
on	O	O
secondary	O	O
punishments	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
crawford	PER	PER
was	O	O
thoroughly	O	O
versed	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
still	O	O
imperfectly	O	O
understood	O	O
science	O	O
of	O	O
prison	O	O
management	O	O
and	O	O
fully	O	O
qualified	O	O
for	O	O
his	O	O
new	O	O
duties	O	O
the	O	O
second	O	O
inspector	O	O
the	O	O
reverend	O	O
which	O	O
force	O	O
russell	PER	PER
was	O	O
the	O	O
chaplain	O	O
of	O	O
milbank	LOC	LOC
penitentiary	O	LOC
great	O	O
architectural	O	O
experiment	O	O
which	O	O
grew	O	O
out	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
strong	O	O
representations	O	O
of	O	O
jeremy	PER	PER
bentham	PER	PER
and	O	O
others	O	O
and	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
first	O	O
national	O	O
recognition	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
principal	O	O
weathers	O	O
crawford	PER	PER
and	O	O
russell	PER	PER
proceeded	O	O
to	O	O
carry	O	O
out	O	O
their	O	O
new	O	O
functions	O	O
with	O	O
commendable	O	O
energy	O	O
and	O	O
without	O	O
a	O	O
moment	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
loss	O	O
of	O	O
time	O	O
the	O	O
ink	O	O
is	O	O
barely	O	O
dry	O	O
upon	O	O
their	O	O
letters	O	O
of	O	O
appointment	O	O
before	O	O
they	O	O
appeared	O	O
at	O	O
newgate	ORG	LOC
and	O	O
commenced	O	O
a	O	O
searching	O	O
investigation	O	O
unlimited	O	O
it	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	ORG	LOC
alone	O	O
newgate	ORG	ORG
indeed	O	O
became	O	O
the	O	O
sole	O	O
seam	O	O
of	O	O
their	O	O
first	O	O
report	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
no	O	O
longer	O	O
the	O	O
faintest	O	O
possible	O	O
excuse	O	O
for	O	O
overcrowding	O	O
the	O	O
numbers	O	O
now	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	ORG	O
an	O	O
occasional	O	O
prisoner	O	O
or	O	O
to	O	O
committed	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
houses	ORG	O
of	ORG	O
parliament	ORG	ORG
the	O	O
courts	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
king	ORG	ORG
'	ORG	ORG
s	ORG	ORG
bench	ORG	ORG
common	ORG	ORG
pleas	ORG	ORG
exchequer	ORG	O
the	O	O
commissioners	ORG	O
of	O	O
bankruptcy	O	O
and	O	O
of	O	O
taxes	O	O
smugglers	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
larger	O	O
number	O	O
sentence	O	O
for	O	O
very	O	O
short	O	O
terms	O	O
temporary	O	O
fences	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
varying	O	O
description	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
central	ORG	O
criminal	ORG	ORG
court	ORG	ORG
but	O	O
incredible	O	O
as	O	O
it	O	O
may	O	O
appear	O	O
the	O	O
authorities	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	ORG	LOC
declined	O	O
to	O	O
avail	O	O
themselves	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
advantages	O	O
offered	O	O
them	O	O
don	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
doubt	O	O
the	O	O
governor	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
time	O	O
being	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
cope	PER	PER
was	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
great	O	O
measure	O	O
to	O	O
blame	O	O
for	O	O
all	O	O
this	O	O
and	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
want	O	O
of	O	O
proper	O	O
classification	O	O
marshall	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
application	O	O
to	O	O
speak	O	O
again	O	O
and	O	O
mouret	O	O
life	O	O
of	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
copes	PER	PER
careless	O	O
and	O	O
perfunctory	O	O
discharge	O	O
he	O	O
blamed	O	O
the	O	O
construction	O	O
of	O	O
new	LOC	O
gate	LOC	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
neglect	O	O
of	O	O
classification	O	O
and	O	O
was	O	O
yet	O	O
compelled	O	O
to	O	O
confess	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
made	O	O
no	O	O
attempt	O	O
whatever	O	O
to	O	O
carry	O	O
it	O	O
out	O	O
we	O	O
didn	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
this	O	O
the	O	O
greatest	O	O
nursery	O	O
of	O	O
crime	O	O
in	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
should	O	O
exercise	O	O
even	O	O
the	O	O
commonest	O	O
care	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
personal	O	O
decency	O	O
or	O	O
comfort	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
prisoners	O	O
i	O	O
always	O	O
smoke	O	O
his	O	O
pipe	O	O
undisturbed	O	O
for	O	O
although	O	O
the	O	O
use	O	O
of	O	O
tobacco	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
prohibited	O	O
since	O	O
the	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
lords	ORG	ORG
committee	ORG	O
nothing	O	O
was	O	O
more	O	O
prominently	O	O
brought	O	O
out	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
inspectors	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
inefficiency	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
governor	O	O
at	O	O
that	O	O
time	O	O
mister	O	O
co	O	O
but	O	O
it	O	O
is	O	O
only	O	O
fair	O	O
to	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
coat	PER	PER
to	O	O
state	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
himself	O	O
said	O	O
he	O	O
went	O	O
whenever	O	O
he	O	O
could	O	O
find	O	O
time	O	O
and	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
not	O	O
the	O	O
least	O	O
part	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
blame	O	O
imputed	O	O
to	O	O
him	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
made	O	O
special	O	O
favourites	O	O
of	O	O
particular	O	O
prisoners	O	O
retaining	O	O
of	O	O
his	O	O
own	O	O
accord	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
edward	PER	PER
gibbon	PER	PER
wakefield	PER	PER
who	O	O
spent	O	O
three	O	O
years	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
a	O	O
little	O	O
before	O	O
the	O	O
time	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
inspectors	O	O
first	O	O
report	O	O
said	O	O
with	O	O
justice	O	O
that	O	O
incredible	O	O
scenes	O	O
of	O	O
horror	O	O
occur	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
it	O	O
was	O	O
more	O	O
over	O	O
in	O	O
his	O	O
opinion	O	O
undoubtedly	O	O
the	O	O
greatest	O	O
nursery	O	O
of	O	O
crime	O	O
in	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
most	O	O
popular	O	O
being	O	O
the	O	O
x	ORG	ORG
morning	ORG	ORG
herald	ORG	ORG
morning	ORG	ORG
chronicle	ORG	ORG
on	O	O
sunday	O	O
the	O	O
weekly	ORG	ORG
dispatch	ORG	ORG
and	O	O
the	O	O
weekly	ORG	ORG
messenger	ORG	ORG
novels	O	O
/	O	O
songs	O	O
play	O	O
books	O	O
such	O	O
as	O	O
jane	PER	PER
shore	PER	PER
grimm	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
german	O	O
tails	O	O
with	O	O
crookshanks	O	O
illustrations	O	O
one	O	O
of	O	O
these	O	O
published	O	O
by	O	O
stockdale	ORG	PER
the	O	O
inspector	O	O
styled	O	O
a	O	O
book	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
most	O	O
disgusting	O	O
nature	O	O
the	O	O
donation	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
philanthropic	O	O
gentleman	O	O
captain	O	O
brown	PER	PER
but	O	O
these	O	O
particularly	O	O
the	O	O
bibles	O	O
for	O	O
a	O	O
little	O	O
appearance	O	O
of	O	O
having	O	O
been	O	O
used	O	O
a	O	O
lad	O	O
named	O	O
matthew	PER	PER
white	PER	PER
has	O	O
had	O	O
a	O	O
wound	O	O
in	O	O
his	O	O
eye	O	O
by	O	O
a	O	O
bone	O	O
thrown	O	O
at	O	O
him	O	O
which	O	O
very	O	O
nearly	O	O
destroyed	O	O
vision	O	O
watkins	PER	PER
disney	PER	ORG
joint	O	O
is	O	O
very	O	O
severely	O	O
injured	O	O
a	O	O
prisoner	O	O
baxter	PER	PER
is	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
infirmary	O	O
in	O	O
consequence	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
severe	O	O
injury	O	O
to	O	O
his	O	O
wrist	O	O
joint	O	O
watkins	PER	PER
case	O	O
referred	O	O
to	O	O
above	O	O
is	O	O
made	O	O
the	O	O
subject	O	O
of	O	O
another	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
special	O	O
report	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
surgeon	O	O
he	O	O
was	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
transport	O	O
side	O	O
when	O	O
one	O	O
of	O	O
his	O	O
fellows	O	O
in	O	O
endeavoring	O	O
to	O	O
strike	O	O
another	O	O
prisoner	O	O
with	O	O
a	O	O
large	O	O
poker	O	O
missed	O	O
his	O	O
aim	O	O
and	O	O
struck	O	O
watkins	PER	PER
knee	O	O
famous	O	O
female	O	O
side	O	O
where	O	O
the	O	O
ladies	ORG	O
association	ORG	O
still	O	O
reigned	O	O
supreme	O	O
more	O	O
system	O	O
and	O	O
a	O	O
greater	O	O
semblance	O	O
of	O	O
decorum	O	O
was	O	O
maintained	O	O
the	O	O
separation	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
sexes	O	O
was	O	O
not	O	O
in	O	O
deed	O	O
rigidly	O	O
carried	O	O
out	O	O
in	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
as	O	O
yet	O	O
could	O	O
also	O	O
at	O	O
any	O	O
time	O	O
for	O	O
tea	O	O
coffee	O	O
and	O	O
sugar	O	O
to	O	O
mrs	O	O
brown	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
shop	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
inside	O	O
the	O	O
female	O	O
gate	O	O
some	O	O
member	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
ladies	ORG	ORG
association	ORG	ORG
observed	O	O
and	O	O
commented	O	O
upon	O	O
the	O	O
fact	O	O
that	O	O
a	O	O
young	O	O
rosy	O	O
-	O	O
cheeked	O	O
girl	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
kept	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
governor	O	O
from	O	O
transportation	O	O
committed	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
house	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
commons	ORG	ORG
who	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
lodged	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
governor	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
own	O	O
house	O	O
the	O	O
last	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
four	O	O
is	O	O
said	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
been	O	O
a	O	O
clergyman	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
church	O	ORG
of	O	ORG
england	LOC	ORG
condemned	O	O
for	O	O
forgery	O	O
a	O	O
miserable	O	O
old	O	O
man	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
tattered	O	O
suit	O	O
of	O	O
black	O	O
the	O	O
ordinary	O	O
of	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
is	O	O
an	O	O
orthodox	O	O
unaffected	O	O
church	O	O
of	O	LOC
england	LOC	LOC
divine	O	O
heads	O	O
of	O	O
lord	O	O
castlereagh	PER	PER
and	O	O
lord	O	O
sydney	PER	PER
being	O	O
carried	O	O
away	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
bag	O	O
munson	PER	PER
try	O	O
to	O	O
fly	O	O
to	O	O
country	O	LOC
on	O	O
the	O	O
detection	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
fraud	O	O
but	O	O
was	O	O
arrested	O	O
at	O	O
plymouth	LOC	LOC
just	O	O
as	O	O
he	O	O
was	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
point	O	O
of	O	O
leaving	O	O
england	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
the	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
packet	O	O
sister	O	O
jean	PER	PER
went	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
coach	O	O
sent	O	O
for	O	O
him	O	O
and	O	O
elijah	PER	PER
.	O	O
27	O	O
york	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
west	LOC	LOC
commercial	LOC	LOC
road	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
was	O	O
about	O	O
to	O	O
emigrate	O	O
to	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
south	LOC	LOC
wales	LOC	LOC
when	O	O
he	O	O
was	O	O
arrested	O	O
at	O	O
islington	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
committed	O	O
to	O	O
newgate	LOC	LOC
on	O	O
a	O	O
charge	O	O
of	O	O
receiving	O	O
stolen	O	O
goods	O	O
they	O	O
presented	O	O
themselves	O	O
about	O	O
noon	O	O
one	O	O
day	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
dissecting	O	O
room	O	O
of	O	O
king	LOC	LOC
'	LOC	LOC
s	LOC	LOC
college	LOC	LOC
hospital	LOC	LOC
accompanied	O	O
by	O	O
a	O	O
third	O	O
man	O	O
green	PER	PER
acre	PER	PER
when	O	O
tried	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
old	LOC	LOC
bailey	LOC	LOC
admitted	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
guilty	O	O
of	O	O
manslaughter	O	O
one	O	O
night	O	O
a	O	O
quantity	O	O
of	O	O
plate	O	O
was	O	O
stolen	O	O
from	O	O
windsor	LOC	LOC
castle	LOC	LOC
another	O	O
time	O	O
buckingham	LOC	LOC
palace	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
robbed	O	O
one	O	O
called	O	O
his	O	O
sister	O	O
but	O	O
supposed	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
his	O	O
wife	O	O
had	O	O
occupied	O	O
a	O	O
room	O	O
in	O	O
south	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
manchester	LOC	LOC
square	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
manning	PER	PER
was	O	O
transferred	O	O
to	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
lodge	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
horse	O	O
munger	LOC	LOC
lane	LOC	LOC
jail	O	O
where	O	O
her	O	O
husband	O	O
soon	O	O
afterwards	O	O
joined	O	O
her	O	O
show	O	O
crafts	O	O
emoluments	O	O
word	O	O
guinea	LOC	LOC
per	O	O
week	O	O
and	O	O
then	O	O
extra	O	O
guinea	O	O
for	O	O
every	O	O
execution	O	O
the	O	O
sufferer	O	O
was	O	O
a	O	O
porter	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
chatham	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
dover	LOC	LOC
railway	O	O
sentenced	O	O
to	O	O
death	O	O
for	O	O
shooting	O	O
the	O	O
stationmaster	O	O
at	O	O
dover	LOC	LOC
when	O	O
asked	O	O
said	O	O
they	O	O
would	O	O
spare	O	O
his	O	O
life	O	O
if	O	O
he	O	O
would	O	O
navigate	O	O
the	O	O
ship	O	O
for	O	O
them	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
river	LOC	LOC
plate	LOC	LOC
or	O	O
buenos	LOC	LOC
aires	LOC	LOC
about	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
time	O	O
a	O	O
body	O	O
was	O	O
discovered	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
line	O	O
near	O	O
the	O	O
railway	LOC	O
bridge	LOC	O
by	O	O
victoria	LOC	LOC
park	LOC	LOC
last	O	O
of	O	O
all	O	O
the	O	O
cadman	PER	O
swore	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
bought	O	O
the	O	O
very	O	O
hat	O	O
found	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
carriage	O	O
for	O	O
mueller	PER	PER
at	O	O
the	O	O
hatters	O	O
walkers	O	O
of	O	O
crawford	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
there	O	O
was	O	O
no	O	O
mystery	O	O
about	O	O
his	O	O
departure	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
gone	O	O
to	O	O
canada	LOC	LOC
by	O	O
the	O	O
victoria	LOC	LOC
sailing	O	O
ship	O	O
starting	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
london	LOC	LOC
docks	O	O
and	O	O
bound	O	O
to	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
launcher	O	O
was	O	O
then	O	O
tracked	O	O
to	O	O
north	LOC	LOC
kent	LOC	LOC
terrace	LOC	LOC
new	LOC	LOC
cross	LOC	LOC
where	O	O
are	O	O
mr	O	O
.	O	O
and	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
campbell	PER	PER
resided	O	O
this	O	O
was	O	O
obviously	O	O
made	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
frequent	O	O
sessions	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
central	ORG	ORG
criminal	ORG	ORG
court	ORG	ORG
and	O	O
the	O	O
utilization	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
two	O	O
subsidiary	O	O
prisons	O	O
in	O	O
giltspur	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
south	LOC	LOC
war	O	O
but	O	O
the	O	O
condition	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
great	LOC	LOC
city	LOC	LOC
jail	O	O
was	O	O
evidently	O	O
considered	O	O
a	O	O
reproach	O	O
by	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
thora	LOC	LOC
tees	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
a	O	O
year	O	O
after	O	O
the	O	O
opening	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
new	O	O
model	O	O
at	O	O
pentonville	LOC	LOC
i	O	O
completed	O	O
imgur	LOC	LOC
bell	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
great	O	O
walls	O	O
of	O	O
babylon	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
mighty	O	O
city	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
of	O	O
his	O	O
exalted	O	O
power	O	O
larosa	PER	PER
'	O	PER
s	O	O
a	O	O
priest	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
temple	LOC	LOC
of	LOC	LOC
bel	LOC	LOC
at	O	O
babylon	LOC	LOC
writing	O	O
about	O	O
2	O	O
:	O	O
50	O	O
bc	O	O
nevada	LOC	LOC
just	O	O
was	O	O
taken	O	O
prisoner	O	O
in	O	O
babylon	LOC	LOC
on	O	O
the	O	O
3rd	O	O
of	O	O
march	O	O
has	O	O
been	O	O
cyrus	PER	PER
entered	O	O
babylon	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
proclaimed	O	O
peace	O	O
to	O	O
all	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
history	O	O
mentions	O	O
the	O	O
names	O	O
of	O	O
two	O	O
of	O	O
its	O	O
later	O	O
rulers	O	O
the	O	O
palace	O	O
of	O	O
nebuchadnezzar	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
occupied	O	O
by	O	O
alexander	PER	PER
the	PER	O
great	PER	PER
brown	PER	PER
on	O	O
which	O	O
babylon	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
spread	O	O
is	O	O
left	O	O
now	O	O
desolate	O	O
nothing	O	O
standing	O	O
in	O	O
that	O	O
peninsula	O	O
between	O	O
the	O	O
euphrates	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
tigris	LOC	LOC
deep	O	O
down	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
mound	O	O
the	O	O
germans	O	O
discovered	O	O
the	O	O
palace	LOC	O
of	LOC	O
nebuchadnezzar	LOC	LOC
with	O	O
its	O	O
hundreds	O	O
of	O	O
small	O	O
chambers	O	O
and	O	O
it	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
huge	O	O
surrounding	O	O
walls	O	O
upon	O	O
a	O	O
little	O	O
mound	O	O
juma	O	O
farther	O	O
on	O	O
and	O	O
eric	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
village	O	O
has	O	O
long	O	O
stood	O	O
activities	O	O
at	O	O
parkland	LOC	LOC
memorial	LOC	LOC
hospital	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
return	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
presidential	O	O
party	O	O
to	O	O
washington	LOC	LOC
vice	O	O
president	O	O
johnson	PER	PER
and	O	O
governor	O	O
connally	PER	PER
on	O	O
june	O	O
5th	O	O
1963	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
cortez	LOC	LOC
hotel	O	O
in	O	O
el	LOC	LOC
paso	LOC	LOC
texas	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
president	O	O
had	O	O
spoken	O	O
earlier	O	O
that	O	O
day	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
air	ORG	ORG
force	ORG	ORG
academy	ORG	ORG
in	O	O
colorado	LOC	LOC
springs	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
original	O	O
plan	O	O
called	O	O
for	O	O
the	O	O
president	O	O
to	O	O
spend	O	O
only	O	O
one	O	O
day	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
state	O	O
making	O	O
whirlwind	O	O
visits	O	O
to	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
-	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
san	LOC	LOC
antonio	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
fbi	ORG	ORG
office	O	O
in	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
gave	O	O
the	O	O
local	O	O
secret	O	O
service	O	O
representatives	O	O
the	O	O
name	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
possibly	O	O
dangerous	O	O
individual	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
area	O	O
who	O	O
was	O	O
investigated	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
president	O	O
would	O	O
arrive	O	O
and	O	O
depart	O	O
from	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
love	LOC	LOC
field	LOC	LOC
that	O	O
a	O	O
motorcade	O	O
through	O	O
the	O	O
downtown	O	O
area	O	O
of	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
the	O	O
luncheon	O	O
site	O	O
should	O	O
be	O	O
arranged	O	O
1936	O	O
as	O	O
testified	O	O
that	O	O
the	O	O
traditional	O	O
parade	O	O
route	O	O
in	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
a	O	O
long	O	O
main	LOC	O
street	LOC	O
since	O	O
the	O	O
tall	O	O
buildings	O	O
along	O	O
with	O	O
street	O	O
the	O	O
route	O	O
chosen	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
airport	O	O
to	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
the	O	O
normal	O	O
one	O	O
except	O	O
where	O	O
harwood	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
selected	O	O
as	O	O
a	O	O
means	O	O
of	O	O
access	O	O
to	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
parallel	O	O
to	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
one	O	O
block	O	O
north	O	O
to	O	O
reach	O	O
the	O	O
northbound	O	O
lanes	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
is	O	O
via	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
route	O	O
number	O	O
77	O	O
traffic	O	O
is	O	O
instructed	O	O
to	O	O
follow	O	O
in	O	O
this	O	O
part	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
city	O	O
from	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
forms	O	O
the	O	O
base	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
triangle	O	O
three	LOC	LOC
streets	LOC	LOC
commerce	LOC	LOC
main	LOC	LOC
and	O	LOC
elm	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
branches	O	O
off	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
right	O	O
that	O	O
is	O	O
used	O	O
by	O	O
traffic	O	O
going	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
-	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
turnpike	O	O
from	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
across	O	LOC
elm	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
the	O	O
access	O	O
road	O	O
to	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
and	O	O
the	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
-	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
turnpike	O	O
in	O	O
order	O	O
to	O	O
reach	O	O
the	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
-	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
turnpike	O	O
which	O	O
has	O	O
the	O	O
same	O	O
access	O	O
road	O	O
from	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
as	O	O
does	O	O
the	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
quote	O	O
apparently	O	O
will	PER	PER
luke	PER	PER
through	O	O
the	O	O
downtown	O	O
area	O	O
probably	O	O
on	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
route	O	O
from	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
love	LOC	LOC
field	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
quote	O	O
from	O	O
the	O	O
airport	O	O
the	O	O
president	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
party	O	O
will	O	O
proceed	O	O
to	O	O
mockingbird	LOC	LOC
lane	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
lemon	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
then	O	O
to	O	O
turtle	LOC	LOC
creek	LOC	LOC
turning	O	O
south	O	O
to	O	O
cedar	LOC	LOC
springs	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
then	O	O
west	O	O
on	O	O
main	O	O
turning	O	O
back	O	O
to	O	O
elma	LOC	LOC
houston	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
then	O	O
out	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
trade	ORG	ORG
mart	O	O
harwood	PER	PER
to	O	O
maine	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
elm	LOC	O
under	O	O
the	O	O
triple	O	O
underpass	O	O
to	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	O	O
and	O	O
onto	O	O
the	O	O
trademarked	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
-	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
san	LOC	LOC
antonio	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
both	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
papers	O	O
cited	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
house	LOC	LOC
sources	O	O
on	O	O
september	O	O
26th	O	O
as	O	O
confirming	O	O
the	O	O
president	O	O
'	O	O
s	O	O
intention	O	O
to	O	O
visit	O	O
texas	LOC	LOC
on	O	O
november	O	O
21	O	O
and	O	O
22	O	O
stevenson	PER	PER
was	O	O
jeered	O	O
jostled	O	O
and	O	O
spat	O	O
upon	O	O
by	O	O
hostile	O	O
demonstrators	O	O
outside	O	O
the	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
memorial	LOC	LOC
auditorium	LOC	LOC
theater	O	O
and	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
would	O	O
visit	O	O
san	LOC	LOC
antonio	LOC	LOC
houston	LOC	LOC
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
dallas	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
austin	LOC	LOC
during	O	O
the	O	O
afternoon	O	O
president	O	O
kennedy	PER	PER
dedicated	O	O
the	O	O
us	ORG	ORG
air	ORG	ORG
force	ORG	ORG
school	ORG	ORG
of	ORG	ORG
aerospace	ORG	ORG
medicine	ORG	ORG
at	O	O
brooks	LOC	LOC
air	LOC	LOC
force	LOC	LOC
base	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
the	O	O
intersection	O	O
of	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
which	O	O
marks	O	O
the	O	O
beginning	O	O
of	O	O
dealey	LOC	LOC
plaza	LOC	LOC
from	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
motorcade	O	O
turn	O	O
right	O	O
and	O	O
went	O	O
north	O	O
on	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
passing	O	O
tall	O	O
buildings	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
right	O	O
spectators	O	O
were	O	O
still	O	O
thickly	O	O
congregated	O	O
in	O	O
front	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
buildings	O	O
which	O	O
line	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
east	O	O
side	O	O
of	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
but	O	O
the	O	O
crowds	O	O
didn	O	O
'	O	O
t	O	O
abruptly	O	O
along	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
special	O	O
agent	O	O
hill	PER	PER
with	O	O
scanning	O	O
the	O	O
few	O	O
people	O	O
standing	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
south	O	O
side	O	O
of	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
after	O	O
the	O	O
motorcade	O	O
had	O	O
turned	O	O
off	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	O
traveling	O	O
at	O	O
speeds	O	O
estimated	O	O
at	O	O
times	O	O
to	O	O
be	O	O
up	O	O
to	O	O
70	O	O
or	O	O
80	O	O
miles	O	O
per	O	O
hour	O	O
down	O	O
the	O	O
stemmons	PER	PER
freeway	O	O
and	O	O
harry	PER	PER
hines	PER	PER
boulevard	O	O
unmarked	O	O
police	O	O
cars	O	O
took	O	O
the	O	O
vice	O	O
president	O	O
and	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
johnson	PER	PER
from	O	O
parkland	LOC	LOC
hospital	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
love	LOC	LOC
field	LOC	LOC
air	ORG	ORG
force	ORG	ORG
one	O	ORG
landed	O	O
at	O	O
andrews	LOC	LOC
air	LOC	LOC
force	LOC	LOC
base	LOC	LOC
where	O	O
president	O	O
kennedy	PER	PER
had	O	O
begun	O	O
his	O	O
last	O	O
trip	O	O
only	O	O
31	O	O
hours	O	O
before	O	O
given	O	O
a	O	O
choice	O	O
between	O	O
the	O	O
national	LOC	LOC
naval	LOC	LOC
medical	LOC	LOC
center	LOC	LOC
at	O	O
bethesda	LOC	LOC
maryland	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
armies	O	O
walter	LOC	LOC
reed	LOC	LOC
hospital	LOC	LOC
with	O	O
three	O	O
secret	O	O
service	O	O
agents	O	O
a	O	O
company	O	O
president	O	O
kennedy	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
body	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
45	O	O
-	O	O
minute	O	O
automobile	O	O
trip	O	O
from	O	O
andrews	LOC	LOC
air	LOC	LOC
force	LOC	LOC
base	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
the	O	O
hospital	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
southwest	O	O
corner	O	O
of	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
looking	O	O
north	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
depository	O	O
building	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
directly	O	O
in	O	O
front	O	O
of	O	O
him	O	O
fisher	PER	PER
testified	O	O
that	O	O
about	O	O
10	O	O
or	O	O
15	O	O
seconds	O	O
before	O	O
the	O	O
motorcade	O	O
turned	O	O
onto	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
from	O	O
main	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
look	O	O
like	O	O
he	O	O
was	O	O
looking	O	O
down	O	O
towards	O	O
the	O	O
trinity	LOC	LOC
river	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
triple	O	O
underpass	O	O
down	O	O
at	O	O
the	O	O
end	O	O
toward	O	O
the	O	O
end	O	O
of	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
probably	O	O
walked	O	O
east	O	O
on	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
seven	O	O
blocks	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
corner	O	O
of	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
murphy	LOC	LOC
it	O	O
was	O	O
the	O	O
intersection	O	O
near	O	O
lamar	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
it	O	O
was	O	O
near	O	O
poydras	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
lamar	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
she	O	O
boarded	O	O
the	O	O
marsalis	ORG	ORG
bus	O	O
st	LOC	LOC
paul	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
streets	O	O
to	O	O
return	O	O
home	O	O
she	O	O
testified	O	O
further	O	O
quote	O	O
south	O	O
on	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
southwest	O	O
across	O	O
the	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
viaduct	O	O
to	O	O
service	O	O
the	O	O
oak	LOC	LOC
cliff	LOC	LOC
area	O	O
along	O	O
marsalis	LOC	LOC
across	O	O
houston	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
front	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
depository	O	O
building	O	O
past	O	O
the	O	O
triple	O	O
underpass	O	O
into	O	O
west	LOC	LOC
dallas	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
south	O	O
on	O	O
beckley	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
walk	O	O
from	O	O
beckley	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
neely	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
1026	O	O
north	LOC	LOC
beckley	LOC	LOC
was	O	O
x	O	O
by	O	O
commission	ORG	ORG
council	ORG	ORG
at	O	O
5	O	O
minutes	O	O
and	O	O
45	O	O
seconds	O	O
greyhound	ORG	ORG
bus	O	O
station	O	O
at	O	O
lamar	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
jackson	LOC	LOC
streets	LOC	LOC
where	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
entered	O	O
whaley	ORG	ORG
'	ORG	ORG
s	ORG	ORG
cab	O	O
was	O	O
eating	O	O
lunch	O	O
at	O	O
his	O	O
cab	O	O
which	O	O
was	O	O
parked	O	O
on	O	O
packing	O	O
facing	O	O
the	O	O
southeast	O	O
corner	O	O
of	O	O
10th	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
patton	LOC	LOC
avenue	LOC	LOC
a	O	O
few	O	O
feet	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
north	O	O
just	O	O
prior	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
shooting	O	O
mrs	O	O
.	O	O
helen	PER	PER
markham	PER	PER
a	O	O
waitress	O	O
in	O	O
downtown	LOC	O
dallas	O	LOC
was	O	O
about	O	O
to	O	O
cross	O	O
10th	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
at	O	O
patton	LOC	LOC
is	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
ran	O	O
south	O	O
on	O	O
patton	LOC	LOC
avenue	LOC	LOC
toward	O	O
jefferson	LOC	LOC
boulevard	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
was	O	O
moving	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
direction	O	O
of	O	O
a	O	O
used	O	O
car	O	O
lot	O	O
but	O	O
only	O	O
two	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
four	O	O
discarded	O	O
cartridge	O	O
cases	O	O
found	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
lawn	O	O
at	O	O
10th	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
patton	LOC	LOC
avenue	LOC	LOC
or	O	O
of	O	O
winchester	ORG	ORG
western	O	O
manufacturer	O	O
this	O	O
is	O	O
earlean	PER	PER
roberts	PER	PER
the	O	O
housekeeper	O	O
at	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
rooming	O	O
house	O	O
i	O	O
'	O	O
m	O	O
the	O	O
last	O	O
person	O	O
known	O	O
to	O	O
have	O	O
seen	O	O
him	O	O
before	O	O
he	O	O
reached	O	O
10th	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
patton	LOC	LOC
avenue	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
was	O	O
seen	O	O
running	O	O
along	O	O
jefferson	LOC	LOC
boulevard	LOC	LOC
that	O	O
a	O	O
jacket	O	O
was	O	O
found	O	O
under	O	O
a	O	O
car	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
lot	O	O
of	O	O
joining	O	O
jefferson	LOC	LOC
boulevard	LOC	LOC
from	O	O
neely	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
oswalds	PER	PER
would	O	O
have	O	O
traveled	O	O
downtown	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
beckley	LOC	LOC
bus	O	O
across	O	O
the	O	O
commerce	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
viaduct	LOC	LOC
an	O	O
aerial	O	O
photograph	O	O
of	O	O
dealey	LOC	LOC
plaza	LOC	LOC
shows	O	O
that	O	O
elm	LOC	LOC
street	LOC	LOC
runs	O	O
at	O	O
an	O	O
angle	O	O
it	O	O
will	O	O
examine	O	O
his	O	O
defection	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1959	O	O
his	O	O
subsequent	O	O
return	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
his	O	O
life	O	O
here	O	O
has	O	O
indicated	O	O
above	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
started	O	O
to	O	O
read	O	O
communist	O	O
literature	O	O
after	O	O
he	O	O
and	O	O
his	O	O
mother	O	O
left	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
moved	O	O
to	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
quote	O	O
i	O	O
lee	PER	PER
harvey	PER	PER
oswald	PER	PER
do	O	O
hereby	O	O
request	O	O
that	O	O
my	O	O
present	O	O
citizenship	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
of	LOC	LOC
america	LOC	LOC
be	O	O
revoked	O	O
i	O	O
have	O	O
entered	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
for	O	O
the	O	O
express	O	O
purpose	O	O
of	O	O
applying	O	O
for	O	O
citizenship	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
through	O	O
the	O	O
means	O	O
of	O	O
naturalization	O	O
while	O	O
it	O	O
was	O	O
apparently	O	O
intended	O	O
for	O	O
publication	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
is	O	O
in	O	O
many	O	O
respects	O	O
critical	O	O
of	O	O
certain	O	O
aspects	O	O
of	O	O
life	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
seemed	O	O
to	O	O
place	O	O
him	O	O
in	O	O
a	O	O
situation	O	O
in	O	O
which	O	O
he	O	O
could	O	O
not	O	O
live	O	O
with	O	O
satisfaction	O	O
either	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
or	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
wooden	O	O
servile	O	O
conformity	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
wishes	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
in	O	O
anticipation	O	O
of	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
russia	LOC	LOC
'	O	O
s	O	O
complete	O	O
domination	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
american	O	O
continent	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
political	O	O
activities	O	O
after	O	O
his	O	O
return	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
united	LOC	LOC
states	LOC	LOC
center	O	O
around	O	O
his	O	O
interest	O	O
in	O	O
cuba	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
fair	O	O
play	O	O
for	O	O
cuba	LOC	LOC
committee	O	O
he	O	O
received	O	O
a	O	O
letter	O	O
from	O	O
somebody	O	O
in	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
some	O	O
communist	O	O
probably	O	O
from	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
i	O	O
'	O	O
m	O	O
not	O	O
sure	O	O
from	O	O
where	O	O
from	O	O
some	O	O
communist	O	O
leader	O	O
and	O	O
she	O	O
was	O	O
very	O	O
happy	O	O
on	O	O
september	O	O
29th	O	O
1863	O	O
mrs	O	O
payne	PER	PER
in	O	O
her	O	O
two	O	O
children	O	O
arrived	O	O
in	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
from	O	O
a	O	O
trip	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
east	LOC	LOC
coast	O	O
saudi	O	O
officials	O	O
of	O	O
both	O	O
cuba	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
the	O	O
soviet	LOC	LOC
union	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
mexico	LOC	LOC
city	LOC	LOC
enroute	O	O
from	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
love	LOC	LOC
field	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
quote	O	O
on	O	O
its	O	O
way	O	O
to	O	O
the	O	O
trade	O	O
mart	O	O
on	O	O
stemmons	LOC	LOC
freeway	LOC	LOC
in	O	O
1789	O	O
in	O	O
less	O	O
time	O	O
than	O	O
it	O	O
took	O	O
george	PER	PER
washington	PER	PER
to	O	O
travel	O	O
from	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
york	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
mount	LOC	LOC
vernon	LOC	LOC
obtaining	O	O
clearance	O	O
of	O	O
some	O	O
categories	O	O
of	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
house	LOC	LOC
employees	O	O
and	O	O
all	O	O
tradesmen	O	O
who	O	O
service	O	O
the	O	O
white	LOC	LOC
house	LOC	LOC
from	O	O
return	O	O
to	O	O
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
to	O	O
move	O	O
to	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
stating	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
distributed	O	O
its	O	O
pamphlets	O	O
on	O	O
the	O	O
streets	O	O
of	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
this	O	O
information	O	O
did	O	O
not	O	O
reach	O	O
agent	O	O
hosty	O	O
in	O	O
dallas	LOC	LOC
until	O	O
june	O	O
and	O	O
that	O	O
they	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
married	O	O
in	O	O
fort	LOC	LOC
worth	LOC	LOC
and	O	O
live	O	O
there	O	O
until	O	O
coming	O	O
to	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
had	O	O
told	O	O
the	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
arresting	O	O
officers	O	O
that	O	O
he	O	O
had	O	O
been	O	O
born	O	O
in	O	O
cuba	LOC	LOC
the	O	O
fbi	ORG	ORG
representative	O	O
in	O	O
mexico	LOC	LOC
city	LOC	LOC
arranged	O	O
to	O	O
follow	O	O
up	O	O
this	O	O
information	O	O
with	O	O
the	O	O
cia	ORG	ORG
and	O	O
to	O	O
verify	O	O
oswald	PER	PER
entry	O	O
into	O	O
mexico	LOC	LOC
he	O	O
had	O	O
received	O	O
a	O	O
copy	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
report	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
office	O	O
which	O	O
contained	O	O
agent	O	O
quigley	PER	PER
'	O	O
s	O	O
memorandum	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
interview	O	O
in	O	O
the	O	O
new	LOC	LOC
orleans	LOC	LOC
jail	O	O
on	O	O
august	O	O
10th	O	O
two	O	O
of	O	O
the	O	O
agents	O	O
returned	O	O
to	O	O
their	O	O
rooms	O	O
the	O	O
seven	O	O
others	O	O
proceeded	O	O
to	O	O
an	O	O
establishment	O	O
called	O	O
the	O	O
cellar	ORG	ORG
coffee	ORG	ORG
house	O	O
